Are you asking me what I want to say?
I'm thinking about it.
How about we do a self-introduction first?
Oh, okay.
Actually, I have written a self-introduction in my PPT.
My PPT has a problem.
Wait a minute.
Okay, let me introduce myself.
Actually, I don't have much of a profile.
I'm just an ordinary three-dimensional person.
The main page of my PPT is this.
I think many people know it.
Actually, the first video I posted was on Bilibili's main page.
So many people know me.
And then I posted the video.
I don't think many people watch it.
Yes.
And then my real name is Wu Hongbin.
I posted it.
You see, it's different from the teacher in the Tan Zhou drama.
I can say my real name.
I mainly do film and television animation.
I mainly did lighting and rendering at the beginning.
Later, because of some of the company's arrangements,
I started to do some synthesis and some simple special effects.
And then I've done three-dimensional animation and two-dimensional animation.
Two-dimensional animation.
I'm also good at drawing the kind of two-dimensional effects of fireworks.
And then for three-dimensional effects, I can do all the processes.
And then from 2011 to 2017,
I also do a personal short film every year.
And then after I started posting videos on Bilibili,
I stopped doing short films.
Okay.
And then I also shot a wedding before.
And then it was not popular to shoot that kind of wedding movie.
I also shot a wedding.
And then I also made a mobile phone game with my friends.
It was around 2013.
And then the mobile phone online games at that time were actually rare.
But at that time, the mobile phone online games in China had not yet appeared.
That is, it was not yet alive.
So we did a one-step-to-one-step time-to-time RPG at that time.
And then it wasn't so popular.
Then it was disbanded.
And then I was a college teacher at Nanjing Academy of Arts for a while.
It's a regular college teacher, not an extracurricular one.
It's the kind of college teacher that has been choreographed.
And now I'm in...
Now I'm in About CG as the special three-dimensional teacher.
And then do some online content.
That's it.
About CG is a teaching website.
It's this one.
This website.
I know.
They're pretty famous.
Yeah.
Actually, a lot of people don't know.
We're mostly famous in the industry.
And then in the group of people who don't do three-dimensional work,
they don't really know us.
We've actually been doing it since 2004.
We've been doing it for more than ten years.
Almost 20 years.
Oh.
Got it.
OK.
So it's a very comprehensive self-introduction.
And then I'm active in Bilibili.
And ArtStation is also the main page.
If you're interested, you can follow it.
This is my ArtStation main page.
OK.
If you're interested, you can also follow MD official.
Thank you.
OK.
And then I'm going to talk about this today.
The first half is about me.
The content I'm sharing.
And then the second half is about Hsueh-Li.
The content is about the costume clothes.
The content of the costume dress.
Yes.
And then.
What else?
Whose live room is this?
This is MD China's live room.
Actually, we are.
Clash of Clans.
No, I'm talking about our company.
Another company.
This is the host of another software.
OK.
That CLO3D is actually very useful.
You may not know.
MD Marvelous Designer and CLO.
CLO3D is a company.
And then Marvelous Designer is mainly focused on this.
It's for video animation and game direction.
And then CLO3D is mainly for the costume industry.
And then there will be a lot of professional costume production functions.
I feel that Ada's introduction to our company software is also.
It feels more familiar than us.
No, no, no.
Because I used it a long time ago.
There was no Marvelous Designer at that time.
Only that CLO3D.
And then I saw that Konami.
That's the little old man.
When he was doing that Metal Gear 5.
When Metal Gear 5.
He was not.
There was a demonstration at that time.
That's the hero of their Snake.
The costume suit he was wearing.
It's made of that costume plating software.
But he didn't write that.
The name of the software for the costume.
So I went to find out.
Which software did he use?
Because he was very professional at that time.
The plating is very similar to the real clothes.
And he also cooperated with the clothing store.
It's with the clothing store.
Cooperation also made the clothes.
The real clothes are sold.
And then I thought.
Wow, this software is really great.
And then I went to find it.
Oh, it's called CLO3D.
And then CLO3D came out.
Marvelous Designer is specifically for the film industry.
And then I slowly learned.
Because in fact our company's software.
At first I wanted to give it to some costume companies.
But in the middle.
I don't know why.
Suddenly there are people in the CG industry.
I feel like your software.
It seems to be able to use the CG aspect.
Yes, it's very useful.
After he said this.
Our boss.
They said.
It seems to be like this.
Then I opened a Marvelous Designer.
Yes.
At first.
But in fact.
The main thing is that the little old repairman.
He promoted it all at once.
And then I saw it later.
The asset group of the industrial film film.
Also started.
The director of the asset group.
What's his name?
And then he also used Marvelous Designer.
And then he shared a set.
It's more suitable for the film industry.
This kind of process.
He shared it.
So everyone slowly started.
All started using MD.
Yes, thank them.
We are also.
Because I started doing clothing.
Clothing design.
And then I got in touch.
I first got in touch with the crew.
And then it turned to Marvelous Designer.
And then opened.
Domestic Marvelous Designer.
Team.
And then I started.
In fact.
I just want to use Marvelous Designer.
At that time.
When I came to our school to promote.
I said.
Wow.
This looks great.
Because at that time.
When promoting.
There was an attack.
And then I said.
Oh, that's great.
I have to go to this company.
And then after I got into the company.
There was only Clue at that time.
And then Marvelous Designer.
It was in 2019.
Just opened.
The distribution here in China.
And then I was in the company.
Just say.
Why don't you try.
You like MD so much.
Start doing some MD.
And then it was established.
After that.
Because I like to watch.
Those cartoons.
And then I opened one.
I said.
We can go to BB.
Make some live awards on it.
And then I opened.
The account of the station.
And then at the beginning of this account.
I saw.
The one made by Ada.
Raymo.
And then I said.
I said.
This person is great.
Because at that time.
I'm not.
A business entrepreneur.
So I'm actually.
These concepts.
It's not very big.
And then I said.
Wow.
It's amazing.
As a result.
At that time.
Jimmy.
He said.
At that time.
Jimmy.
We told Jimmy.
Go.
Take a look.
What are some of the more famous.
3D artists.
And then Jimmy.
He told me right away.
Ada.
Ada is great.
I said.
Oh.
And then I clicked on the hand.
Look.
Wow.
This is me.
When I just created MD.
I said.
Wow.
This is amazing.
This is made by Raymo.
And then I said.
Wow.
It's actually Ada.
And then we thought.
Do you want to invite Ada.
Oh.
Not Ada.
As our guest.
I didn't expect.
Just ask Ada.
Ada agreed very quickly.
I just wanted to say.
Wow.
This is.
The positive pursuit.
I got it.
Just suddenly started to blow each other.
My face is red.
No.
This.
This is.
Ah.
Is.
Official.
Official benefits.
Can be positive and bright.
Pursuit.
Haha.
Business.
Pursuit.
Payment.
I thought.
Payment pursuit.
I'm sweet.
Hahaha.
If there are.
There are.
Some listeners are in the clothing industry.
Actually.
You can also try.
Close3D is very easy to use.
Close3D.
He.
He can do that.
Just different code.
He can do the code.
For example.
What is your number S and M?
And he can do that.
Staples.
That's the one.
You.
The board.
On the machine.
The plating on the machine.
The circuit board.
He can make that circuit board.
It's also convenient.
There are many previews.
It's also very useful.
Okay, let's call it a day.
Okay, then I'll start talking about today's topic.
Okay.
Okay, today I'm mainly going to talk about the role of Lin Guang as an example.
Then I'll share with you the actual process of making Three Beautiful Girls.
I'm mainly going to talk about the process.
Because to be honest, when you're making a character or a more complex project,
the process is actually more important than the use of the software.
Sometimes if you don't do the process right, or if there's a problem with the connection in the middle,
it might actually cause the whole character to be a mess, or the scene to be a mess,
or the whole thing takes a long time to do.
If your process and thinking are more clear and smooth,
it will make you do this.
It will make you do the process.
It's very smooth.
And it can even get better results.
So what I'm mainly going to share with you this time is its process.
The use of specific software.
You can go and see the corresponding tutorials.
For example, the MD tutorial.
In the MD China page, there are actually a lot of MD-related tutorials.
If you're interested, you can go and see them.
I won't go into too much detail about the specific operation.
I'm just going to talk about the process of this character.
And then this character.
I've posted a video on my main page before.
It's here.
This character.
This character is Lin Guang.
This is a horse's ear, not a rabbit's ear.
Lin Guang is a character in The Daydream.
And then he's a heavy-duty character with a shield.
And then I have a production process here.
I posted it before.
I can put it down for you to take a look.
If you haven't seen it, you can take a look first.
This is the MD part.
I used Manless Designer to do the whole costume.
I'll talk about it in detail later.
Six-edged soldier.
Yes, this character is...
His character is six-edged.
I also added Lin Guang's golden ear to it.
It's too straight.
I brushed my hair yesterday and brushed it until midnight.
The hair only hair can grow.
It's long, so it'll grow a little.
With that hair, I'm not sure how to cut it.
But it'll grow back.
Don't worry.
I'll make it as long as I can.
Ah, this...
What's the direct comment on confessing?
That's weird.
I still don't know if the music is still there
I'm not sure
I'm so tired
The most powerful song, I think
I can't sing it
I'm not sure
I don't know
How many girls do you want to eat?
I can't help it.
Oh, is there a current sound?
Is there a current sound like this?
Oh, there's a current sound, right?
Is there a current sound now?
I'll take this a little further.
I think I might be the one who said the comments.
Because I might be away from my other computer.
This video is actually very short.
Only three minutes.
But it shows a lot of different types of software.
And a very complex process.
So a lot of people,
if they just watch this video,
it's actually just for fun.
Right?
It's actually hard to know a detailed process from the inside.
But I think it's fine.
You can watch the video,
and tell me what you think.
Thank you for your time.
You are welcome.
Thank you for watching this video.
I'll see you next time.
Bye-bye.
If you like this video,
please subscribe to my channel.
See you next time.
Bye-bye.
Thank you.
If you know how to play 3D, you can probably understand it.
If you don't know how to play 3D, you will be confused.
Or if you are a beginner, right?
The videos I posted on Bilibili
are actually just to
get you interested in 3D.
For teaching, this kind of open video
has no educational purpose.
So you just think it's good to watch.
Right?
Then I will talk about
the main software used
in this video.
It's Maya, Marvelous Designer,
ZBrush, Substance Painter,
and Mamoset Toolbag.
You all know about Maya.
It's an Autodesk software.
And Marvelous Designer
is the main unit
of today's live stream.
Marvelous Designer makes clothing software.
ZBrush is a sculpting software.
It's a 2.5D sculpting software.
Substance Painter
was acquired by Adobe.
It's now Adobe Substance Painter.
It's mainly used to make materials
and stickers.
Mamoset Toolbag
is commonly known as Eight Marbles.
It's a real-time rendering software.
You can also use it to sculpt.
The character you see on the left
is actually
a character made
with Lin Guang at the same time.
Lin Guang is a character
I made last summer.
I did it for about a year.
At that time,
I used to make competitive characters.
I saw some foreign bosses
on Artstation.
They tried to make some
portraits.
I think it was
19 or 20 years ago.
I think it was 19 or 20 years ago.
At that time,
many of them made
some portrait effects.
I thought it was very good.
I was wondering if I could
make a full-body competition.
But I made it realistic.
I made it realistic.
I put it in Eight Marbles and tried it.
I was not familiar with UE4 at that time.
I tried it.
I was like,
I will make a simple character
to verify the process.
So, I made Kailou.
This character is also a reality.
You can see that the quality
is close to the performance.
SP Steam is more than 300 per month.
Yes.
Md is available on Steam.
You need to buy its personal license
It's available on Steam.
Yes, I bought it on Steam, and then from the end of last year, I thought about it, because it was discounted every year on Christmas, I said that I would buy another one on Christmas, and then I found that it was gone.
Yes, because we bought it on Steam in the past, it seems that there will be some problems, and then we changed it to buy it directly on the official website.
Yes, but now it is also a subscription system, and it is also a account system, so it is actually used in the same way as Steam, and the price is actually the same.
As a productivity tool, the price is actually the same as that of some other software that I usually use. For example, I use Redshift and other software, and it is only two or three thousand yuan a year.
In fact, the price is almost the same. As a productivity tool, the price can be accepted.
Okay, then the character of Kailu tried to do a real-time role to verify the process, and it turned out to be pretty good.
The effect is pretty good.
And then this character actually has a tutorial.
I actually have a tutorial on AobaoCG.
If you are interested, you can take a look.
Okay, do an advertisement, and then continue.
Today, I would like to share the whole process of Lin Guang, because I did not teach Lin Guang.
Then it is mainly divided into these four pieces.
The first piece is about some simple processes of how the basic model is obtained.
Then the second step is to talk about this costume, and then the third step is to talk about some details and the fourth step is to talk about rendering.
Then the third step is to talk about some details and the fourth step is to talk about rendering.
Finally, after I finish talking about the whole process, I will actually demonstrate MD.
What is the process of MD to ZBrush that I use?
Because if the model of MD is directly lead to ZBrush to carve, there may be some problems, so we generally have a transmission process.
I will go to the scene to demonstrate the process in detail.
Then the following content may be relatively dry.
If you don't understand, you can ask me in the comments.
Just ask me in real time, I will also answer in real time.
Because if you really don't know 3D,
If you are a third-party or a third-party beginner, some of the things in the direction of the process may be a little bit dry.
OK, let's take a look.
So first of all, the first one is the basic model part.
In fact, it was because I wanted to get a basic model quickly.
Because I want to achieve the whole process quickly.
If it's a competition model, we usually make a model that takes at least more than 100 hours.
This process is particularly long.
So I will try to reduce some of the production time in the middle.
For example, if you are in the company, there will be some standard models in the company's software server to provide you with.
But if you are a personal user, you can't use the company's material, right?
So how to get a quick and easy-to-use material or a relatively effective material?
I chose the DAZ software on my side.
This is the DAZ Studio software in the upper left corner.
I didn't open the sticker, so it shouldn't matter if it's live or not.
Which one?
DAZ Studio.
OK.
The DAZ Studio software.
The DAZ Studio software is an asset-oriented software.
It is mainly used to let you read all kinds of materials and then make a final product.
Of course, you can also use it directly to get a competitive or animated effect.
But relatively speaking, this software is relatively light.
It has a lot of functions that are not complete.
And it's not so comfortable to use.
Because it's not a core-oriented 3D software after all.
It's a light 3D software.
It's for hobbyists.
It can't build or do anything.
It can only drag in the existing material and light it up.
It's just a software like that.
But one of its advantages is that its role as a material is actually very good.
If you want a DAZ asset, I bought this on its official website.
The assets on its official website are very cheap.
If you take advantage of me and buy its members,
it's actually very cheap to buy it a role for just a few dozen dollars.
And you just buy one or two and it's actually enough.
Then I just use it.
And I bought it.
Then I bought it.
So, uh, so, this is a software called DAZ Studio.
This software is called DAZ Studio.
Through its so-called, uh, DAZ to Maya, such a plug-in, a transfer is done.
That plug-in is just in this script.
Just click it and you can directly, directly in the Maya.
There is also a corresponding plug-in above this one.
There is a corresponding plug-in above this one.
After you click it, it will read the same FBX and it will introduce the entire character into Maya.
And it's bound to you.
You're bound to it.
So?
So you can go straight to this game.
The same FBX can import the entire character into Maya,
and it will bind it for you.
You have a binding.
So you can use this software directly.
You can use this character directly,
and you can make this character as a particle
and make it into the character you want.
And this character has a binding,
and it has the material attached to the body.
You can use it directly.
You can do it based on it.
In fact, it saves a lot of time.
I used this software when I made Zululand.
Before I made this Zululand character,
there were few people who were professional in making three-dimensional characters using this software.
After I made the Zululand video,
this software suddenly became popular,
and people who painted it also thought it was good.
Then many people who can draw with three-dimensional support also started using this software.
So now this software,
the material is also out,
and the official has also released a lot of Asian face models.
After I finished that video,
there may be a lot of Asian face models in the Asian market.
And it also has a lot of this kind of interface between software.
It also came out with a Genesis 8 to Maya interface.
It's easier to use than this Daz to Maya.
It can also be used.
But that one is more expensive.
And Daz to Maya is free.
So if you don't want to spend money,
you can use Daz to Maya directly.
Then what about this side?
Then this,
then I can use this model to make a big shape in this Maya.
This may look a little silly,
but it's actually very important.
This step is with this,
including when you do the scene,
you have to go to the white box.
In fact, it has the same effect,
that is, you need to have a general draft,
you need to have a general concept in your mind,
that is, what kind of image it is,
and then what parts it has, right?
It has, it needs to create a general feeling.
So here,
I can turn on the,
my file,
show you the file of Maya.
OK, so this is the block file at the beginning.
In addition to the clothing part,
this clothing part,
I was a,
I was just putting on one of these,
this kind of feeling of clothing.
OK, then in addition to these clothes,
then this character itself is the one used,
this is the best start,
the gray color,
I'm going to put on this gray color.
This is the model,
this is the model used to create,
then I added a cartoon to his skeleton,
very simple, right?
Then when it falls in,
he is actually,
ah,
wait a minute,
I'm in the class,
when it fell in,
it will also give you,
all of the blind shape based on the space of the skeleton,
all of them fall in,
so that he is,
For example, the shoulder of the night blind will be deformed very seriously, right?
If you use this plug-in, all the blind shapes in this space will be deformed, so it will not be deformed, which is very easy to use.
In addition to this, I created a blind shape myself.
Why do I use a blind shape? This is actually a process problem.
If you go directly to edit the model, then it will not be able to retain the binding of your model, right?
Your binding will be a problem. So how do you keep the binding and then achieve a sculpting function?
I used Maya's virtual editor, which is its new blind shape.
This is a function that came out after 2017 update 3.
Using it, I can directly sculpt on a good molded model.
This is the first character that fell in. It looks like this.
I used a blind shape group to achieve a function similar to the sculpting layer.
But at the same time as the sculpting,
it can retain the effect of the original binding.
This is one of my uses in the process.
Is there a current?
Is there a current again?
Wait a minute.
There is indeed a current.
Now?
Because I can't hear my reflection here.
Is there any more?
Really?
Wait a minute.
Because I can't hear the sound of the live broadcast room.
I can only hear the sound of the live broadcast room.
It is indeed a very loud current sound.
I also heard it here.
Then occasionally it will be a little bigger and occasionally it will be a little smaller.
Wait a minute.
Is it okay?
Okay, okay.
Okay, and then continue.
After I got such a basic model,
I can go back to the T-pose anytime.
For example, when I go to engrave and edit it,
I can engrave in Maya directly.
I can also pour it to the
In the first half of the video, I will talk about the process of my character.
In the middle, I will use AMD, and then I will show you the process of my AMD.
The second half will be the process of AMD, and the content will be made entirely by AMD.
Since this model can go back to T-Pose,
I can also carve it into ZBrush,
and then I can add it to the Bladeshape after I carve it back from ZBrush.
So this is a very flexible process.
You can keep the binding of this character,
and you can also use some related functions to carve it,
so that it can produce some changes.
This will be very convenient, and you can get a post with this kind of post very quickly.
And you can go back anytime.
And the face is a model of the face you carved.
And it includes all the material of the skin.
But because of the live broadcast here, I can't open it for you to see.
If I open it, I guess the supervisor will rush over right away.
Because actually, I want to speak quickly, so you can see it more clearly.
If I speak too slowly, it's actually relatively sleepy.
On Saturday, you guys might want to play games, so I'll try to speak as quickly as possible.
And this is a large model.
What is this large model?
It makes me look at the screenshot.
You can see it like this, right?
When you look at the screenshot, you find that the final effect is not bad.
I'm a little confident.
And you probably know, I probably know the last one.
That big model.
That big model. I probably know, I probably know the last one.
What do you want to look like?
The screenshot is very important.
If you don't do the screenshot,
your last thing might be, for example, crooked or something.
So try to make a screenshot.
And this is my first step, which is to have a body.
So after you have a body.
After you have a body.
The next step is to do the costume.
Because of this role, it's because you want to play a role, right?
In fact, more than 50% of the time, I'm doing his clothes.
Because in fact, except for his face, you usually play a normal role.
That is to say, that kind of very exposed role.
You may need a lot of time to put it on his body.
In fact, like Lin Guang, this kind of character that is almost covered by clothes.
Basically, he's just a face that's out there.
He doesn't have a place to be out there.
So this body, he's mainly giving you a reference.
And then the face is mainly what he's going to show.
All the other parts are clothes.
So it actually takes a lot of time to make this costume.
So I, because I was doing the Zorolan before.
Including some of the previous works.
I'm actually using MD.
It's okay.
It's also more skilled.
So I'm still going to use this MD to make it.
I'm going to make his clothes.
There's a current sound again.
He can't carve in any other pose.
He can only carve under T-pose or A-pose.
After carving, you turn it into a blind shape.
After that, you turn it into a pose.
You turn it into a pose.
So it can both ensure the effect of your original carving.
It can also ensure that he has a pose.
It's a process like this.
If you want to carve, you have to go back to the original binding pose.
Carving is the only way.
Is there still a current sound now?
Yes.
I want to see it for a little while.
I'm not up to it.
How desperate!
So desperate!
Oh, that doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter.
Ada, you continue talking.
I'm going to change the headphones.
Oh, fine, fine, fine.
All right.
Okay, I'll keep talking.
And then this is what I'm going to use MD to make his clothes.
Uh, what about his clothes?
It includes the one that, uh.
the soft fabric part and the hard armor part.
So the armor part can't be made with AMD.
So except for the armor part,
I use AMD for all the other clothes.
And finally, I put the AMD model into ZBrush to carve.
So AMD can get this kind of clothing effect very quickly.
You can see this on the screen.
This is what I did at the beginning and what I did at the end.
So this dress is actually very simple.
This dress is very simple.
You can go to AMD official website to learn more about this.
I won't go into details.
In fact, there is nothing special about the process of making the armor.
What is the most complicated thing about this whole dress?
The most complicated thing is its skirt.
I used the skirt in the preview.
And then I made it longer.
It's that simple.
I didn't do it manually.
And then the armor of the clothes is actually relatively simple.
I just made some straight lines.
And then I put it on first,
and then I adjusted it.
Because in fact,
because in fact,
AMD,
this software,
it's in real time.
You can make a big shape first,
and then you can adjust it slowly.
Just look at it in real time.
The picture is slowly dragging and adjusting.
In fact, it is very convenient.
And then can AMD make shoes?
In fact, it can be done.
It may be a little bit more complicated.
You can do it if you want to.
It's possible.
Simple.
And then the main process problem is AMD.
How do I make my character,
but there is a post in it?
This is a problem.
And this is a big part of the software.
Most of the tutorials I haven't seen, right?
The scarf is surrounded by a very long triangle cloth.
If you look at this in the video,
you may see this,
see this clip, right?
Where's my AMD?
Why is it gone?
Wait a minute.
I'll turn on my MD.
Marvelous designer.
Something like this.
Clothes, wrinkle.
You just have to,
AMD is like this.
You just have to let him put it on.
You open the resolution.
He automatically has clothes wriggly.
No need for you to carve.
It is completely automatically settled.
So this software,
you want to achieve some of this wrinkled effect.
Actually it's completely automatic,
very stupid.
The main problem is actually in some processes.
It can be adjusted to this,
喂,现在是正常的吗?有电流吗?
有,呃,不是,有声音,呃,电流好像没有,但是感觉声音在好像在很远的地方里。
哦,没有,因为我离它很远,现在呢?
哦,可以可以,可以。
好的好的,有电流的话,弹幕可以跟我讲一下,因为我今天在家直播,我没有想到它会有这么大的电流声。
OK,啊,然后这个就是这个最早我做的这个,一开始做的这个基础模型,其实你们可以看到,就是这个版片,如此的简单,对吧?
就啥都没有,其实也没有什么细节,因为我当时想的是,细节主要靠雕刻嘛,然后你这边只要让它穿起来,然后你正常解算,这这些皱褶就自然产生了,没有什么,呃,就其实真的很简单的。
就是你们非说这个我的那个,
口头禅是简单,因为它确实很好用嘛。
然后主要是一个问题,就是说怎么把动作导进去。
那么MD的动作其实是一个,呃,其实是有很多的解决方案的。
那么首先是我的模型因为当时去,呃,用了DAZ的这一套流程,所以呢,它是有这个动画在里面的。
所以呢,我可以一个,我可以把整个动画导出去,那么整个动画导出去呢,又分为两种流程。
又分为两种流程。
首先我可以用FBX导。
那么MD是完整的支持FBX的动画的,所以我可以把F,我可以直接导FBX。
我也可以导ABC,就是alimbic这样的一个缓存文件,那么它也是支持alimbic的。
包括它还支持这个MDD的缓存文件,它也是支持的。
所以其实我有很多的选择。
那么除了导这个动画的话,我也可以用morph,也就是blind shape这样的。
我把A pose和B pose导进去的话,它也可以实现一个动画效果。
所以其实有很多选择,那么我可以演示一下上面的这个ABC的流程,然后再演示一下AB的流程。
就是AB pose的流程。
那么首先ABC的话非常简单,就是你直接选中这个角色。
我把这个整个角色的模型一起选中吧。
然后你在它的这个缓存这边,然后你找到alimbic。
然后所有软件都可以啊,只要支持ABC都可以。
然后你把它点这个将当前选择导述到alimbic。
然后开始结束的话是1到10嘛。
然后其他其实也没有啥,你就把详细。
UV写入去处空间名称写入颜色及面积整整世界空间。
应该就可以了嘛,没有什么。
然后直接把它导出去就可以了。
然后我们放在这个这里,比如说pose test。
然后它会导出一个带有动作的这样的一个缓存文件。
刚才你可以看到它动了一下。
然后之后其实很简单的,我就是直接在这个MD里面。
我把我们原先的这个模特删除了之后。
你在这里导入选这个alimbic。
然后你找到这个MD里面的这个刚才我导出的这个ABC文件打开。
然后它这里会问一个尺寸。
我是厘米的尺寸。
然后加载类型点打开。
然后我是24帧每秒。
是24帧吗?我看一下。
30帧每秒。
打开打那个30帧。
其实无所谓了,因为毕竟不是做动画。
OK,那这个时候你导入进来的这个角色。
你可以看见好像没有什么变化嘛。
实际上它是在这个Animation里面。
你就可以看到它其实是有动画的。
然后这个角色就可以在这个软件里面去动起来。
看到了吗?
那么有了这个动画之后。
你再在这个所有的版片这边。
我把版片的那个粒子数调小一点。
那么你把这个版片解锁。
解锁之后。
我快一键了,怎么没用了。
因为没开写动。
好了。
不是。
刚是K的嘛。
然后我输入法的问题。
然后那个你这边直接解算的话。
你会看到它这个是正常的在你第一个Post上面的嘛。
然后你就可以直接在这个Animation里面。
然后就可以去进行一个解算。
那么它就会衣服就会直接贴在你的这个Post上。
产生一个这样的带动作的这样的一个效果。
看到了吗?
然后你可以再去调高你的粒子数。
比如说在我就不再演示了。
因为毕竟在直播。
然后你再去进行进一步的解算。
就可以获得一个带有Post的这样的一个效果。
然后你还可以去新版本的话。
可以直接把这个风直接在这开。
以前要在那个显示还是哪里的我忘了。
以前要在哪里开的。
显示的环境设置里面。
对。
或者是在这个右键里面。
好像有个模拟属性。
然后这边调。
然后现在直接就可以在这调开之后点一下。
你就可以调这个风。
然后你在这风你可以激活打开。
然后你调一个力度缩减值什么的。
然后把它调一个方向。
然后你再解算它就会吹着衣服跑了。
就是这样的一个效果。
有没有很简单对吧。
很简单。
真的没有很复杂。
你们看我几分钟就做完了吗。
OK。
然后基于这个。
然后我们可以直接去把它的这个模型。
就是我们可以把它这个服装模型的去导出。
然后把它放在这个。
然后得到了这样的模型嘛。
然后可以把它放到Zbrush里面。
那中途呢还有一个。
还有一个。
那中途呢还有一个流程呢。
就是说MD的那个模型啊。
你如果想要去拿去雕刻的话呢。
其实是很就是很不好用的。
因为你可以看到它的模型是这个样子的。
OK。
这个模式。
它模型是这个样子。
诶为什么诶。
那个模式在哪这个。
它的模型是这个样子。
就是它是一个三角面的模型。
那么它官方其实提供了几种方案。
但是我感觉都不是很好用。
所以我主要还是用我自己的一套那个流程传递的方案。
那套方案呢最早是工业光模的一个大佬分享的。
然后后来大家都在用。
我觉得也是不错的。
等会儿会分享给大家。
等会儿会分析一下各种传递的方式。
以及具体操作啊。
这个等会儿再说。
然后继续往下。
那么传递完成之后呢。
我会后面再说。
他的步线很诚情。
他的步线非常精致。
最后uto的的效果。
Message box,
我们换这个 autre的手机。
找人来打,
然后我就来这个让他到達,
景 curves,
这样拍下来如何成功。
对,
现在也可以给我看位子。
正是这一段呀,
我看好了!
!!
又是脖子的这个mercy了。
像我之前提到的 prizes already,
还有呢就想要给 coloca。
然后呢这个部分呢。
脖子的 vemos一对这र org tab,
好,
这裏有着ay的页,
哎呀!
领后一路就 Cerahi看出来呢。
If it is lagging, it is normal to go to the normal lagging
Just slowly lagging like this
I turned on 12x speed to see faster
It's like this, and then it lags slowly
Then do it, do it, do it, do it
There is nothing like this
There is actually no secret to this, just do it slowly
Just be patient
Then do chest armor, shoulder armor, weapons, and so on, just do it slowly
Based on this costume
This part is actually nothing to look at, and then it looks like this when it's done
Then I can open it for everyone to see the final model is
Armor file
This is a model like this
Then it has this
There is a costume
The one that has been copied is a costume made of pure ground inside, and then all of these models are
Unlimited
Of course, this actually doesn't need to be carved, which is
There will be some details on it at the end, and there may be some sliding or something like that on it
Then this MD costume part will be put in Zbrush to carve
Then this hair part will be made into that, and it will be remade in Zbrush
The weapon part is like this
Then this part is actually a
It's also a detachment from the block you just saw
That part
It's
Its cut and the previous character is the cut of the previous file, which is actually the same, which is
I will match that cut to do this to ensure the consistency before and after
Because sometimes if you don't have a part of the cut in front of you
You may sit and sit and your whole character will deviate
It deviates from the goal you made at the beginning
So this part is very important, that is, you must go to the cut before, you must ensure the consistency before and after
Then this
Then this costume part is finished here, and then it goes into the details and stickers
So because I wanted to say that I was doing a real-time role, a real-time role
Then I certainly can't be like that
I can't do this kind of sticker change, right
Because of the change, the Eight Marbles did not support it at the time. In fact, the new version of the Eight Marbles supported it, but the previous Eight Marbles did not support the change.
So at that time I would still go
Just go to the high film first and then go to the low film
But the low film is actually me
Relatively speaking, the face is quite high, such a low film
Then
Part of the details are partly carved in ZB, and part of them are painted in Substance Painter
Then the carving of ZB is such a carving, of course, you can see that I actually
The main thing I carved was this sleeve part, and then this part was actually not carved, and this part was actually made by the original MD, and it looked pretty good
Pretty beautiful
So I didn't carve either, just guaranteed to keep the original look
You can see
The creator is actually pretty good
If you put his
If you make his example number higher, you can actually see
There are a lot of details, so I didn't carve much, just guaranteed to keep the original look, and maybe strengthen some contrast
Mainly the details of the sleeves are a little less, after all, in the original setting
The original setting feels a bit like a sleeve
So I went to carve some details by hand
So in the end, it's like this, after carving some details, it's like this
Then the hair part
I used the brush of Zbrush to redo it
OK, so in the end, the state of the high mold that I showed you is like this
And then behind it, I didn't do anything, I should carve one here, I'm lazy
I didn't do this
Then this
Only the front part can be seen, but it doesn't matter because it's a competition
How to make a small bag, the small bag is also made of card thread, the small bag is a
It's just a
It's just a card thread model
It's normal in Maya
Card thread
This kind of simple object, in fact, you just need to use the Maya modeling module, it's basically done
What is the texture of the costume
The texture of the costume
The texture of the costume, in fact, the state of the sculptor
The state of the sculptor is actually realized through the branch of MD
That is, after you choose it
It can choose all kinds of previews in this
These previews are some of the real fabrics
So you can achieve all kinds of different effects
Like on that Art Station
There is a
A very good boss
In fact, it has been organized
Arranged a very detailed one
It's a picture of a state where all kinds of different fabrics are presented
You can see it on Art Station's main page
Jade Law
Is this a Brazilian?
OK, it's a picture like this, and then you can see all kinds of different previews
The state of the costume it presents
Hard and soft
Right?
And then there are some
Stretched, hammered, non-hammered, all kinds of these effects
Then you can choose the effect you want
Then you choose here
Then when this fabric is disassembled, it will present the corresponding state
So in fact, it doesn't need you to be too detailed to carry out a texture carving
He actually did it for you
You just have to follow his feeling and do it
Where is the picture on Art Station? If you want it, I will send it to the MD China group later
OK, then this is
This is the carving part
Then after carving, I will just put these
The effect is to use that
I was using SP to carve
Still using
SP, I can't remember that I used that Eight-Wheels to carve
Anyway, I just went to carve a sticker. The process of carving a sticker is actually more mechanical, and there is no skill to do so.
Just normally carve and that's it
And it was carved by myself
So there is nothing too complicated
You just have to separate the objects
Don't let the objects stack together to carve
This will carve out a lot of cross effects
You just separate it and carve it
OK, then this SP, I will use SP to make a sticker
Because it was to implement the effect
Then this SP, it will be easier to do some of the effects of this kind of sticker in the game
Including some of the editing functions of the hair line are better
Then I probably divided 16-7 UVs at that time, and then each UV is 4-5 stickers anyway, so
Plus skin, eyes, hair, etc.
A total of 8-9
About every sticker
Then each one is 8K stickers
Then if you use SP at that time, it will be
Very collapsed, because this SP, it is for this
Support for a large number of this kind of stickers
The support for a large number of this large resolution stickers is not very good, and it does not support Udemy
Caused a lot of pain at that time, which is to turn on a layer, it will take a very long time. You can see that my left side actually adds various effects
And each one is very complicated
Then the whole thing is stuck
Then it is
Right, save large number
Then
I regret it very much
After that, I might still consider using Mario to do it, because Mario
Mario has that
Now there is the function of GeoMesh, it also supports this kind of sticker like a game, and it also has a printer
And it
Mario was born to this
The support for this large-scale sticker is very good, so I may still go back to Mario to make it later.
Because we are doing film, we are still more familiar with Mario
Then you can show everyone here
This
Some of the videos I made at that time
Video video video
Where is my video
Wait a minute, let me find the video, video, video
10, 20
June
June 10
I'm here
Wait a minute, let me see, 12, 16, 11, 13
Yes, 215
Because we can't play this and show everyone
If I open this file or I go live, this kind of
I'm sure I'll hang it all
So I can't open it. I'll show you. The SP file we did at that time looks like this.
Including that
Actually it went on to a lot of that to a large extent but
But it would still be very lag
Let's look at that. This doesn't work out.
You can see some of the details like this.
And then some of the details on the shield.
These are some of the details on the clothes.
Like this.
Some of the details on the shield.
I've been working on this for a long time.
But it's stuck. It's stuck. It's stuck.
And then this one you see is actually only 4K in SP.
Only 4K.
And then when 8K comes out, it's just stuck in the 8-hole.
The whole display is blown up.
And then this is done with SP.
In fact, these details, to be honest, really don't have much technical content.
Just pile it up.
The main thing to note is that you have to follow the real thing.
You can't press the button in vain.
You have to do it according to your imagination.
You have to put some photos.
At that time, I actually found a lot of those,
some of the war damage,
for example, some of the armor used on the battlefield,
some of the shield and armor photos,
real photos,
including the ancient ones from ancient Rome.
It's easy to find them on auction websites.
There are some photos of shields and armor.
And then there are a lot of scratches and scratches on them and something.
And then it's a good reference.
You have to look at some of the references
You don't have to imagine doing it yourself, because I've seen a lot of people do that kind of sketching,
that kind of huge, very regular sketching.
In fact, that kind of thing doesn't exist in the real world.
A lot of sketching actually has a very confusing effect.
So you still have to look for reference.
As for the technology, there really isn't much.
SP is a very easy-to-use, silly drawing software.
You can use some of its material to predict, and then you can also import some of it to draw.
You just need to work on it.
Okay, and then the next part is the rendering part.
So the rendering part is actually a bit of brainless.
Just put those things that were in SP just now,
and then just plug them into the 8-hole, and then plug all the stickers up.
Just plug them up.
Because at that time, I wanted to say that on the one hand, I wanted to do reality,
and on the other hand, I wanted to do the film-level effect.
The film-level effect requires a lot of stickers to achieve that effect, right?
So I just put all the 8K stickers in there.
So at that time, I couldn't turn on the full display mode,
so I turned on a real-time preview mode to see.
At that time, it was barely able to run to more than 30 frames.
And then at that time, it showed such an effect in the window.
I can show you this.
Take a look at the video, because I can't turn it on either.
When this is turned on, the memory is full.
That's what it was like at that time, in the 8-hole.
Wait a minute.
Let me show you this.
Because it's real-time, so it can be compared to that one.
Compared to the front-end display, it can be very convenient to adjust the effect in real time.
So this is real-time.
In fact, what I use is quite happy.
This is the process.
In the end, you can be very convenient.
You can also adjust the intensity of the light, the angle of the light.
And then some backlight, that transparent effect material can also be adjusted in real time.
This is much more convenient than the front-end display.
Because in the front-end display, you can't always adjust it so fluently like a real-time display, right?
And then the last thing I did was a single decision.
It's such an effect.
And then I did some front-end rendering.
That is, you can turn on the resistance to a very high level through the 8-hole.
And then the final rendering is such an effect.
And then put it in Photoshop to do some post-production effects.
What to adjust some of that.
Do some of that gray light effect.
What to do with the skin.
In fact, there is no need to grind the skin.
I don't have any details on my skin.
And then do some color correction or something.
That's it.
And then the words.
What's next?
That is to say, in order to make a sense of presence on the battlefield.
Because I wanted to do the one at the time.
In the first chapter of the game.
They are not in that city.
It's a very hard battle.
And then the light came to save them in time.
I want to make a feeling like that in the street.
So then I went to buy it.
And then I went to buy it.
That's the one from the motion.
That's the one from the waste material package.
But there's a problem with this material package.
It's just that it only has Maya or Max or C4D.
The preset version.
It doesn't have the 8-hole version.
And then I remade all the material circles again.
In the 8-hole.
And then after remaking it.
I'm at the end of this.
I'm going to take this.
I'm going to take these materials.
I went to a very big scene.
Say wait a minute.
Take a look.
Where is it?
It's like this.
I went to a street scene.
I put some waste in the near area.
And then I put some wires and buildings in the distance.
And then I added a fog.
You can see that the effect of adding fog and not adding fog is completely different.
Added a fog.
And then I remade the lighting.
Just let the front one.
What I did at the beginning was actually quite dark.
And then I'm in the front.
And then I added another light in the front.
Just this one.
This one alone.
In fact, you look at the whole scene alone.
It's weird, isn't it?
And then this one.
But from this point of view, there's nothing wrong with it.
In fact, the final effect is not bad.
And then some videos were shown.
Used to post this video on the B站.
And then the final effect is like this.
The actual process.
In fact, it's much faster than that of the film.
That's the kind of competition.
The process of CG is very fast.
After all.
There are many stages of adjustment.
It's all real.
The hair is used.
This hair is made with this.
XGin.
Maya's XGin.
After doing the hair.
The sticker material to be prepared.
And then stick it on.
Just in.
In Librush.
On the hair of this hair.
Like this hair.
I use this hair.
And then use that.
Maya's GMH2.
That plug.
And then I put it.
Cut the end.
Just leave this section in the middle.
Then it's a tube.
Then GMH.
You can use this tube model.
To generate.
Some very fine hair.
Hair.
And then on these hair.
On top of it.
Stick it on.
I'm in XGin.
Use XGin to do the hair.
The sticker of the braiding.
Then you can achieve.
Similar to what you just saw.
The effect of this kind of hair.
This is also a.
In the actual process.
One.
One of my personal ideas.
Because before.
In fact.
If we do the actual hair.
A lot of them will go.
Just one by one.
To put the hair.
But I personally think.
It's not.
On the one hand.
I actually do a competition.
I want to get the effect quickly.
I don't do games.
Because the game.
He is.
The placement and efficiency of the hair.
The demand is very high.
So I will slowly set it up.
But.
I do competition.
In fact, there is no requirement for that.
I just want.
To have an effect.
Then.
I want him to have an effect.
A wholesale.
The one.
The offline.
And then.
His.
Is real-time.
So I think.
That hair with GMH.
Just fine.
Because.
the multi-dimensional hair, it will bug. It can't be used.
Just when I was doing the zero-glow hair, it was
randomly updated. It has not been updated for several years.
It suddenly updated a version, and then that function can be used.
Then it was just right to use it.
Then I went to do this hair, and then the effect was actually quite good.
At that time, I have a video here,
I can take a look.
It's like this.
You can use that hair,
through that model, and then generate this kind of hair with a lot of hair,
this kind of hair with a lot of hair models.
It's actually a multi-dimensional piece, and then this yellow material
is what I'm using in Xgen's hair.
Then I put this material on it,
and it can directly achieve a very good real-time effect.
Although it doesn't show much in Maya,
but if you put it in the real-time rendering software,
you can get a better effect.
In the real-time rendering software,
you can deal with the effect of this alpha rendering.
It's just like Bajo.
Its rendering will not have any problems.
The overall effect is still good.
Then Bajo now has a new version, right?
Bajo now has Bajo 4.
Bajo 4 supports the light tracking effect.
In fact, it will get a better effect.
When I was doing this role, Bajo was still Bajo 3.08.
This is a video tutorial.
If you are interested, you can take a look.
This is the overall process.
Then I will show you how the MD model
is programmed.
This is my personal way of using it.
I turn off ZBrush first,
and then I will open MD.
I will use the preview of this model first.
Let's go to the previewed model first.
Let's see what this model looks like.
I can see this model.
When I turn off ZBrush,
it will automatically turn on the image display.
Yes, because our official website has a lot of appos on it, so maybe we need to change it.
OK, let me do this.
Ah, there's a wind. I forgot.
Now, the GPU resolution is pretty good. If you're interested, you can try it.
But there's a problem with the GPU resolution. It seems like it hasn't been solved yet.
Let's see when the official website can solve this problem.
Yes, this problem is caused by us.
The GPU resolution is not a very complete GPU resolution.
It's just for the purpose of processing and quickly building up the previous clothing.
And when using GPU resolution, especially for multi-layered clothing, there are indeed some wear and tear problems.
Yes, the GPU speed is really fast and super happy.
But this is the problem.
The GPU is constantly being troubled.
It can't do multi-layered clothing or complicated, for example, the effect of the sleeve falling down.
And then the sleeves will be all messed up.
If you use GPU, it's a pity.
We are also doing optimization.
And when will it be released?
I don't know.
OK.
As soon as possible.
On the way.
So now, the process I personally use is that when I make a very complicated clothing, I will use the GPU to calculate a large size first.
After that, I will...
For example, the CPU will first calculate the condition of the clothes.
Then I will turn the particle number to a very high level, for example, to 5 or something like that.
Then I turn it on as GPU.
I click on it and turn it off.
Let it slightly calculate.
Then you can get a very good, very detailed.
The effect.
That's how I use it now.
That's when the GPU can be used completely.
After that, it should be very happy.
And then this one.
For example, now this one is a clothes.
And then let's demonstrate it first.
I don't have to turn it on too high here.
After all, I still try to ensure the smoothness of the live broadcast.
OK.
And now it's a dress like this.
And then I'm going to take it out.
OBJ.
And then I'm going to demonstrate the process of clothing here.
OK.
Then this one.
I'm going to call her Gao Mo.
And then here's the chip.
Don't leave it alone.
Siешьou And thin as well.
And then kill rice.
And then there's nothing else
to decide.
Okay.
So now with this feature, if you want to make it look like the current version,
If you want to make it look neat,
You need to click on the right button here and select the 2D version position.
Then you can place it here a little bit.
Even if your model is high, it is still very smooth in the UV interface of AMD.
This is a part I like very much.
If you put it in Maya or something,
If you put the high-end UV in it again, it will be blocked.
So I usually put the UV in AMD first.
The thing I'm operating now is UV, not a board.
This is UV.
OK, after that, I'll save it first.
Hey, I...
Did I put it in the wrong place just now?
I don't care.
OK, then I'll take the high-end model out.
Out.
I put it in the wrong place.
Put it in the project I'm doing now.
This is the high-end model.
OK.
Then I will also need a model.
It's a flat model like this.
It's a model that doesn't wear on the body.
Then I will pour it out.
Then this is called UV.
UV high-end model.
It's actually a state similar to UV.
Then it's also a setting like this.
Pour out.
Then I'm here.
My general idea is that I will use ZBrush.
To do a re-tap of the model just now.
Then I'll take a look here first.
Hey, I...
This one.
I will put this board in ZBrush.
Then ZBrush has a ZRemesher.
Of course, you can also manually go to the tap.
But I personally still think that the efficiency of using ZBrush's ZRemesher will be higher.
Then here.
I may try to use the same face number for the first time.
Then go to ZRemesher.
Then it will generally get a good effect.
You can see that there will be a little bit of a problem here.
Then maybe, for example, go again.
The settlement may be solved.
OK.
But it has some problems on some corners.
This is a problem of ZBrush itself.
This is not the problem of MD's model.
ZBrush will put some triangular corners to solve the loss.
OK.
I don't know why.
Then I will export it.
Then this is the model of ZB with this new line.
So how do we go?
Our current purpose.
I will import this model first.
This side will go around a little bit.
I want to import this.
There are some problems with the full line of my computer.
Let's import this high model first.
It's like this, right?
Change the background.
Then import this UV-shaped high model.
That is, import the high model of the plate.
Then import this ZB.
Then this ZB.
It is such a line.
It's a horizontal vertical line, right?
Horizontal vertical line.
Then I won't fix it here.
In fact, I might go to fix it.
I will fix these places.
For example, I might fix it here.
Something like this.
Then some corners.
I might go to make up for it.
For example, this side.
Because I'm live streaming.
So I'll just show you a simple demonstration here.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Yes, there might be such a situation.
So I'm afraid.
So I'm not going to fix it anymore.
Let me show you.
So in fact, I just want such a line.
Go to the clothes.
Just let him put it on the clothes.
Because the advantage of such a line is that it is horizontal vertical.
And it doesn't have so many five-star points.
This is usually called a new point.
That's Paul.
Something like this.
In that ZBrush.
Or when it's in a split state.
No matter which software it's in.
The more new points there are.
In fact, in our production.
The more you need to avoid it.
There's no way to carve a smooth point like this.
It will.
It will always pop up.
Or it's always out of line.
It will have one.
There's a very annoying point there.
It will cause your highlights.
When the highlights sweep over here.
He's going to have one of those.
There's a little defect.
It's in the film model.
It's a place to pay special attention to avoidance.
And then.
It's a very annoying point.
There's a little defect.
This is in the film model.
The Is there a place to pay special attention to avoidance?
And then.
Well, the ZBrush.
He gave you the effect of rematch.
It's just that it's better.
That's just that these new points are very few.
You can see only.
There's only two new points like this.
And if you need to manually repair it.
You might be able to move the new point directly to the edge.
Or or move it to some.
Not.
The places that aren't too conspicuous.
It works.
I'm not going to fix it.
And then.
What we're going to do now is.
I need to transfer this line to him.
Go to him.
Transfer to him.
How to send this place to him?
We now need to pass this line to it
How to pass it to this place
How to pass it
You need to use Maya's function called attribute transfer
The function of attribute transfer
Can let you base on
Various different information to pass various different information
So here, first of all
First of all, I need to use this version of us as an intermediary
because
Why is the UV of this version like this
What's going on
I think it's not set up
Oh, maybe there were some problems with the operation just now
When I export it, I put that
No, no, no, no correct output
It's okay, I'll export it again here
This is hi
You need to click on the unified UV coordinates
That's it
Okay, and then I'm going to use this one
This is UV Hi
Click on the unified UV coordinates
Okay, good
It's not a turn over
Okay, I'm going to do it again
Look at this UV
That's right
Okay, you can see it
It has a UV
Why is it in the second line?
Why is it not?
Why is it in 101?
Okay
Okay, and then I'm going to import this
Hey, that's weird
Is it a problem with where I set it up?
Maybe it's a problem with where I set it up
I just exported it
I guess there's something wrong with it
And then this one from ZB doesn't care about it
Because this one from ZB doesn't have a UV
It doesn't have a UV
So how do I do it?
What can I do to pass this line?
Just pass this line to him, right?
Do they have any common common points?
Do they have any common properties to pass?
The real question is that they don't have any common properties to pass
So how do I get it?
I need to use this model here as a middle turn
This model
This this this this
What about the UV?
Oh, I'm going to isolate
Okay
So this model has its UV
And this model is the same as the UV of these two models
Right?
This is their common property
So this model
This model and this model
Their shapes are the same
So we're going to use this model as a middle turn
First of all, I'm going to use the position of the two of them
I'm going to pass the UV of this model to this model with the line rule
And then I'm going to use the UV as a common property
Pass the position of the top of this model to him
Then I can achieve
In the end, you can achieve a model with this shape and this position
But it has this line rule
Do you understand?
Okay, so first of all, I'm going to use this one
I'm going to use this model
And then I'm going to select it
The two of them are selected together
And then I'm going to open it here
And then I'm going to use this one
We use the space in the world to transmit its coordinates
We use coordinates to transmit its UV
And then point transfer
Okay, so you can see our original line rule model
It also has UV
Did you see that?
Yeah, that's it
It's very simple
And then I'm going to use it
Pass its top position to him
And then I'm going to use this one here
The attribute transfer function
So I'm going to use UV to pass the top position
And then click pass
Okay, so you can see this model
It's already here
And it has the same state and shape as the previous model
Okay, so the layout of this model
It's more suitable for carving
And then I'm going to put this model
Into the Zbrush
To carve
And then I'm going to put it in here
And then I'm going to put this in
And then we can carve it happily
Because of a model like this
It's horizontal and vertical
You can give it a detail
It doesn't matter
So if you carve it on top
You can still get a more detailed effect
And then I'm going to open that digital screen here
This part is where I'm in a lot of lessons
A lot of people will have questions
You can see it
You can get a very smooth
Such a carving effect
But if your line is not horizontal and vertical like this
It's possible that it won't be able to do it
The smooth effect comes out
Then there is another problem
That is to say its edge
Its edge
When you are dividing
It will shrink
Right
So what do you do at this time
In fact, there is a way
That is to say
We can use this crease
On this fold here
You can fold the multidirectional group
No, press that
You can give it an automatic group here
Then press the multidirectional group fold
In this way
The edges of each object
There will be folds
At this time you are dividing
Its fold will not change
It will change
It will keep the original shape
And because I am using
Z80 2021.5.1
This version
So it has a new function
Then this is the dynamic detail
After you open the dynamic detail
It can give you an automatic level of smoothness
Right
And then you can do the thickness
You can make a real thickness
In this way
If you make some carvings on it
You can see it
You can see its details
And you can see the thickness
And this thickness
It won't cause any wrinkles
Because of your carving
You can see
It won't have any
This kind of twisted and deviated effect
There is no twisted and deviated effect
It won't get thinner
It won't be what
You smooth it
It doesn't matter
It won't get thinner
It's still this thickness
Because it's a real-time preview
You turn off the dynamic detail
It's gone
That's the effect
So with this brush
This fabric
This is the new dynamic detail function
Then add this
Add this
This is what I just demonstrated
This transmission process
You can make it very conveniently
Make a thick clothing
And then you might say
I don't want it to be so hard on the edge
I want it to be softer
You can turn off the back split surface
And then
But my model has a crease
Right
This is actually a problem
So there is no way to solve it for the time being
And then if there are some places like this
There may be problems in the curved area
Why do you have to keep it to yourself
All right
Then you can increase the smoothness
Open
You can see the twist here
It's solved
OK
In this way
In fact, you can carve
No matter if you're playing games
Make a film
Including hand-made
In fact, it's very convenient
This is a relatively
For the time being
It's the most optimized one
A process
It's a process on the line
And then there's actually another process
It's in this MD
It itself
MD itself has this
First of all, MD has a top function
You don't have to do this
I just save time in the IDB
You can also do it manually
The same
If you cancel the fold
It will shrink
Isn't it just a demonstration?
In MD
It actually has such a function
That is, it can put all the models
To carry out a four-dimensional operation
Some Python mess
It's being changed from
It's okay
Just confirm
OK
You can see
In this MD
It has its own four-dimensional function
It will produce
This is what we call
This kind of
It's all over the place
This thing
It's actually in the film process
Or in that kind of
In the high-end sculpting process
It's very desperate
It's not
There's no way to use this
And then
But
It also had a function
It's this
It's called
What is it called
This reset grid function
This function
It can also produce horizontal value effects
But its edge
It's a little bit of a pity
It's going to be like this
This model
We usually
In fact, this model is very useful
This one
We can use it to do the dynamic analysis
Use it to do the agent model
This is what we say
In Houdini
Or in Maya
Use nclose
This kind of software
To do the analysis
We usually
Use this model
To do the details
Right
For example
Like that
Uh
Like the imagination
He also has a demonstration
Such a process
That is, they will do
Various
Very complex clothing details
On the clothes
But this dress
You have to solve
You can't use that high model
To solve
So at this time
You need a resolution agent model
This is usually the process in the film
So
This model
It's especially suitable
To do that
Resolution agent model
Because it's horizontal
Very convenient
To solve
And its edge
It's point by point
It's completely on the edge
So it's very good
Very easy to use
But it's used for carving
In fact, it's like this
Horizontal vertical model
It's okay
But if
For example
Your model
If it's
If it's like this
There's no way
Just
You
For example
Put it again
And then
For example
You do it again
Then
You can't use it
You can't carve it
Because
Resolution network
Is a memory
So
Resolution network
Is a memory
2G version
If the version is Y
Then
Resolution network
Is also finished
But in fact
There is still one
This
I still have
A simple idea
That is
Wait a minute
I'll put
All of it
This
Y
It's a square
A bug
Oh myino
Why
Swallow
Sh issued
curled
Curled
I also have a way to do this.
When the number of faces of the reset grid is high to a certain level,
there is no problem with resetting the grid.
For example, if I change the number of particles to 5,
the number of faces is very high.
If you reset the grid again at this time,
the area affected by it will be very small.
Even if the entire grid is oblique,
only a very small area will be affected.
Basically, it won't be affected in a large area.
We can actually put this in Zbrush and carve it.
It's just that there will be a little bit of a problem at the edge.
Wait a minute.
V.
It's okay. It should be fine.
Did I go too far?
I'm talking too long.
It's okay.
I can speed it up.
I can speak faster in my part.
Okay.
Then we can import this model into Zbrush again.
Then reset this model.
Okay.
You can see that this model is actually a bit irregular.
There is a problem with its edge.
And it's a little bit away.
At this time, you can do this.
Because it's not merged, you can automatically group it.
After automatically grouping, you can merge it again.
Because its points are all one-to-one.
You can use this limit distance and limit points.
Because this distance is a bit short.
For example, adjust a 5.
It may not be enough.
Adjust a 10.
Okay, you can see that these points are all merged.
Can you see it?
But, for example, if you go to carve, there will be problems with its edges.
There will be some problems with its edges, right?
You are rough.
But at this time, you can use the Shift key.
Then you can use the Shift key to open the Sculpt Trace Pro mode.
Then you can start carving.
I need to turn off the limit level.
Then I use Sculpt Trace Pro to carve.
This mode can make it smooth.
Because it changes its line.
Then your edge will be smooth.
Hey, what's wrong with this?
Conceal the benefits.
There are eight of them.
Just go down with the first stroke.
Solve.
Right?
Hey?
It's so weird.
What's going on?
Why?
Hey?
This is...
This...
No, why does it...
Hmm?
This solves the problem.
But how come the Sculpt Trace Pro is like this?
And the Ctrl Shift A...
No.
Wait a minute.
Ctrl Shift X.
Expand it.
And then Ctrl W.
This becomes a whole.
And then turn it over.
You don't have to turn it over.
Just like this.
And then choose it.
Ctrl W.
Ctrl Shift X.
This solves it.
And then in Zbrush.
If you do this.
But isn't there a hole in the middle?
So it doesn't matter.
So in Zbrush.
There's one.
According to the properties.
Or press the group to throw light.
You can automatically throw this light into the smoothness.
But you might think.
Hey, this whole throw light is not easy to use.
Right?
So in the smooth brush.
He's in that.
He's in his brush case.
There's a group of smooth brushes.
The file holder of the smooth brush.
There's a smooth groups in the file holder.
A brush like this.
So you can change the brush of your Shift.
Switch to smooth groups.
And then.
You turn the intensity up a little bit.
Brush again.
Then he can take this group.
Hey.
Make it smooth.
And then it solves the problem of non-line.
That is to say.
He got a smooth high screen.
And then at this time.
You say.
Hey.
I want to put it in.
What should I do?
That's also very simple.
He has one.
This.
The feature of the characteristic cover.
You can cover it along the edge of the group.
Because you just.
It's combined.
So.
It will automatically have a group like this.
And then you can smooth it out.
Wait a minute.
Blur.
Cover.
The characteristic cover.
Smooth.
Cover it again.
Smooth it again.
And then you just use this moving tool.
To shrink it in.
Oh.
Then you go to use that group.
This smooth function.
You can get one.
Similar to this border of clothing.
Oh.
Learned.
Record it right away.
Because this edge has always been a.
It's a problem that many people will encounter.
Many people have asked me such a question.
And then I've been saying.
Is there any good process?
And then I tried all kinds of methods.
And then.
This.
That's the method just now.
Is.
This.
Thank you. Thank you, MD China.
Thank you, Ada.
If you have any questions, feel free to ask.
Come on, ask.
Here comes the Q&A session.
Why do I see a single question mark?
It's nice.
Thank you, Ada.
What about the processing and naming rules of low-modeling?
Processing and naming of low-modeling.
The naming rules are high and low.
You can see it in the official article of Bajo.
You can see the name line and the name line are low.
Then you can just use that to import it.
It will import a lot.
This is your name.
Then low and name.
You must have the same name.
Then you have to say hi.
Then you import that OBJ into Bajo.
Then Bajo will automatically identify it.
Then what?
Wow, it's a lot.
Processing and naming of low-modeling.
Processing.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Then I love you, too.
I love you, too.
Then Ajun will come out with an MD tutorial.
I actually have an MD tutorial.
I have an MD tutorial in Bajo.
You can search Marvelous Design directly here.
You just search Marvelous.
Then there are a lot of mine.
This is mine.
Then this is also mine.
This is also mine.
I don't know why Ajun is so good.
I'm curious.
I can go take a look.
And then does Max have transfer function?
Max seems to have it.
I'm not familiar with Max.
It seems to be using transformers to pass.
It's not like Maia's kind of pointer.
It is a kind of transmitter type modifier.
Then Blender has an insert.
You can use Blender to have a familiar pass.
You can use the same process as I did in Maia.
MD all teaching.
I went through MD all teaching before.
Okay, good.
You can use it.
人体速磨的软件叫DAZ Studio,DAZ Studio,没拼错,DAZ Studio,然后你去DAZ3D.com就可以看,它官方网站就是这个,你直接搜这个DAZ Studio可以找到。
用DAZ的最难的一点就是下载和安装。
其实因为他们用的都是盗版的,所以会存在安装问题,你用正版安装器全自动安装根本不存在问题。
对,我也觉得,我刚刚看到这个弹幕的时候,我其实在想为什么会有这样的问题。
主要是还有一些第三方素材导入也会有一些问题。
对。
就是正常用官方那个,它现在出了一个叫做,
什么DAZ Hub一样的,叫DAZ Hub,就是一个专门的软件,然后去装素材,都是一键安装,全自动的,根本不用你去设置。
什么时候再开班啊,我可能在五六月份左右吧,会开一个玛雅的,也是一个零基础的课,然后会很入门的内容就是,如果你会玛雅,其实也就没有必要去上。
八核高模烘焙给低模,是不是不用把部件都分开?其实分不分部件,这个是你自己的问题嘛,就是你想分开就分开。
你不想分开就不分开。
你放在一块儿烘的话,它就会互相沾染信息,对吧?你分开的话,它就可以隔离各个部件之间的信息。
呃,QuadroMesh,呃,QuadroRemesher,对,QuadroRemesher是可以用的。
最后那个ZB衣服缝边平滑的那个键,我用的是一个笔刷,叫Smooth Group,是Zbrush自带的一个笔刷。
有一套流程吗?从模型到渲染。
有的呀,就是我在AboutCG上面的很多教程都是这样的。
嗯。
都是完整的流程,你可以去看嘛。
都是从头做到尾的一个完整的,甚至是那个我新出的那个墨瑞干的那个,墨瑞干的那个,包括这个,这个新出的也是一个完整的流程。
然后我出的那个墨瑞干的是我至今为止出的流程最完整的一个东西,就是从一个球开始雕刻出一整个,雕刻出一整个人体,然后做贴图,然后做毛发。
嗯。
然后红背啊之类的,然后绑定,调动画,再导入到U14引擎里面做角色操作,然后让它在U14里面动起来。
一整个教学。
嗯。
不过新手别看了,太复杂了。
多项线流程一般规范是4个项线吗?
不是。
多项线流程的规范是多少个项线啊?99个项线以内都可以吧?
无所谓,100多个项线也可以吧,我记得之前阿芬达的那个飞船就100多页的项线。
没有问题啊。
随便你用多少,但是只能放在第一项线啊,就是你只能放在正x和正y的那个里面。
就是只能在这个里面。
你不能放到这里去,只能放在这边。
就这边的话其实你放多少都无所谓,你再超数据都没有关系,就是只能放在这个范围内。
而且不能跨项线,我发现很多人会跨项线,东西不可,UA不可以跨项线的。
就不可以有一个UA这样斜在这个中间之类的,都是不行的。
怎么把z-bar之后的衣服麻牙解……
麻牙解……解什么?什么?什么?
control-shift-s,不是,我刚才用的是control-shift-x,是扩展选择的功能。
那是z-bar,你们问点MD的功能啊,control-shift-x就是这个功能。
然后control-shift-s是缩小shrink和expand的英文的首字母。
英文的首字母。
嗯,MD预测图我等会儿发群里吧。
初选MD给推荐个你的教程嘛。
其实我的教程上面写了入门或者完全的就是入门的教程。
那个小姐姐也挺好看的,如果你对案例有兴趣,你可以看那个小姐姐的教程。
0到1之间,不是0到1,是正,只要是正数就行。
放负向线对,读取不出来。
解……解……解算。
高模放到码里,没法解算了呀。
解算不了了,不可逆了呀。
只能用包裹流程,但是那个是影视流程。
我如果说那个影视上的那个解算包裹的流程的话,我可能要花掉四五个小时讲,这个不可能在现场讲。
回头你可以看一些专业的教学,它是有专门的流程的。
嗯。
我也在看弹幕,但是感觉好像大家问的MD的问题不是很多。
哈哈。
对,可以,什么叫可以再吟唱一遍。
吟唱一遍什么意思?
可能是希望你再讲一遍吧。
做广告吗?
哈哈。
About CG,十个学CG,九个在这里。
哈哈哈。
大家,大家关注这个MD中国的账号。
and he usually posts a lot of MD teaching.
The atmosphere of the group is really good.
Usually, we will discuss MD technical problems, and then someone will answer them.
It's really good. So if you want to learn MD, you can pay attention to it.
I have also published a lot of MD in the MWC.
There are also many other great authors who have published MD teaching in the MWC.
If you are interested, you can take a look.
I also have a free lecture.
Let me see where it is.
Where is it?
I can't find it. It seems that I have to look for it at the B station.
I have a 2-hour live lecture.
From 0, I did an MA-1 flying jacket with MD.
Then the whole process of rendering was published at the B station.
At the B station,
there is also a CD account.
If you are interested, you can take a look.
It's a complete one.
You don't have to pay for it.
You can just take a look at it.
Yes, I saw our MD's resume.
Welcome to our family.
How many groups are there?
Wait a minute.
I can't memorize it.
If you are interested,
you can add the official group of Marvelous Designer.
Group number 1081139.
Group number 1081139721.
If you are interested, you can add it.
Yes, we have technical support in the group every day.
You can also chat with us in the group.
You can chat with us about anything you want to talk about.
You can also talk about those irrelevant topics.
Yes, welcome to answer.
Hurry up and pick up the phone and order.
Group number 1081139.
Oh no, the chat is flying over.
The chat is flying over.
I can't remember our group number.
We welcome all users to join the group.
Whether you are a folk master
or use the personal version or the corporate version,
you can add it.
You can add it.
And we all provide technical support.
And there are really a lot of big bosses in the group.
They often help solve some problems.
They provide us with different ideas.
Is there an educational version?
Yes, there is.
There is an educational version.
There will be a discount for students.
And there are a lot of student discounts.
But the student discount with our group turns out to be the opening password.
Because before, the number of people in the group almost went online.
Then it was set the opening numbers.
Do students get discounts?
Students get discounts.
The discount is quite high.
I remember it's pretty high.
And if you are interested,
you can come to my group.
Yes, yes.
I think there are a lot of people in this group.
There are almost 3,000 people.
And if you're interested, you can come in and talk about technology and so on.
Right.
5, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 3, 4, 3.
Like this.
OK.
Let's see if everyone has any questions.
No questions.
Is it going to be my turn?
I'm sorry, I added both of them.
OK, I'm done.
OK, how about I share my screen?
Oh, my desktop is also exposed.
What should this be?
Hide up.
And then, OK.
I'm done, I'm done, I'm done, I'm done.
Oh, it's hidden.
Now it's my turn.
Oh, how much is a big group?
Can you report it again?
5, 3, 5, 4, 6, 3, 3, 4, 3.
All right, all right.
My desktop.
I'll put my desktop on the group page next time.
I'll put it on the group page later.
This is a game I've been playing for a long time.
But now there's no one playing it.
And then this Monday has never changed.
Because I really like this game.
Ha ha ha ha.
Yes.
And then that's my part.
And then my part is to introduce you to everyone.
Oh, I don't know if I can hear what I'm saying.
If there is a video, remember to tell me.
Well, my process this time is to make such a set.
A complete set of ancient Western clothes.
Then.
Oh, OK, OK.
And then.
And then this whole set of clothes sits down for about a day and a half.
You can sit down like this in a day and a half.
If you're not familiar with it, you can do it for about two days.
There will be a live broadcast.
And then this complete video of Jasmu.
It will be released next week.
That is to say.
Oh.
Oh, we also have a live broadcast this week.
That is, we usually have two live broadcasts.
One is the video recorded when the live broadcast is recorded.
And one is the audio version.
In the audio version, the words are added subtitles.
Uh, there is no later dubbing.
But because everyone said that the operation speed was too fast.
So this time the operation speed process is.
One to one speed.
Uh, make sure you can do it according to that step.
And then the whole video is about an hour and a half.
This whole set of clothes.
Okay.
Then we'll start talking.
And then it's actually very simple at first.
That is, when I'm making this dress.
I'll make him a skirt first.
Of course, if you have a skirt, you can skip this step.
The skirt is usually a chasing.
A chase.
You just have to put it around your model.
What I'm doing here is to make a skirt in Marvelous Designer.
First of all, I'm going to use some fabric for his belt.
And then he won't fall down.
For example, it's a plus.
Or say it's a change of one of his attributes.
Because usually our skirt.
His skirt is a little bit bigger.
He'll drag his belt down.
So you might want to change a fabric.
For example, like a relatively hard fabric like a leather.
Make your belt not easy to transform.
And so it won't be pulled down by the skirt.
And then.
Just change some physical attributes.
For example, I might change the waistband.
This one.
Elasticity.
It's the same.
It's actually like strengthening this belt.
Let him not fall down.
Because ordinary skirts.
His skirt.
Everyone knows it's wide and long.
And then he's bound to wear your belt.
There are some shapes.
So.
Just change his physical attributes like this.
And then I add a skirt.
Usually when I add a skirt.
I usually add more details.
Just add a little bit.
I won't say.
Add a lot at a time.
And then I'll change him to a fabric.
You can see the fabric that was originally cotton.
When the fabric was changed to leather.
The skirt popped up all of a sudden.
By changing.
You can also change the bending strength.
It's going to make the skirt a little bit more open.
As a skirt.
There are a lot of this kind of western skirt.
There will be a big skirt in it.
There are some friends.
You might want to record an animation in MD.
If you don't have a skirt.
Just chasing.
The kind you do in other 3D software.
Put it in the action.
You can just use this method.
To do a skirt.
Just can be animated together.
And then.
It's going to add another layer outside.
After adding another layer.
In fact, it's also for.
Just let this part inside.
A little more.
Yes.
A little more of this part inside.
A little more.
Can make this skirt look better.
Because in.
Some.
This should be one.
This is.
The dress from the 18th century.
When the dress was in.
They are all in it.
Most of the dress is called dress.
I saw in the skirt.
There was also that that I saw.
The reference search on the web.
Put in the skirt.
They have some noble women.
Will be.
Put bird feathers in the back of the skirt.
Use bird feathers to do dress.
I feel very strange.
How can.
Use bird feathers to do dress.
I have some past videos.
I saw that there is also a big one that uses the bones of the goldfish.
Yes, and this has been passed down to the bones that use the goldfish now.
So in the clothing industry, they still manage those things called dragon bones or gold bones.
That is to say, part of it is used to support it.
Of course, it is no longer used very regularly because it is very cruel, but it used to be.
Then, through some modifications to the sewing line, you can fold the front, that is, the fold of the front of the board.
Originally, the skirt may be as wide as the front and back, but through your modifications to the sewing line,
you can make the fold of the front less, and the fold of the back more, so that the front is more flat, and the back is more protruding.
Of course, these steps are all because I don't know how to sew the skirt,
so
if you want to make such a skirt in MD, or if you want to build a basic skirt in other 3D software, you don't have to do these steps.
Then I saw that the gold bone was opened, and this is also an old mobile game player.
After that, adjust these skirts, and then adjust the skirt.
Adjust the stress of the skirt, when you apply a positive pressure to the skirt paper,
because the pressure will expand, it will stretch your skirt.
After that, I will insert a default system dress, because I want to start making top clothes,
I can't imagine. I often slack off, I don't like to draw my own panels.
I usually just drop a default set of clothes, and then come out to roll out this set of clothes.
That's it.
So I came up with the idea to make this outfit
Is it too fast?
It's okay, I'll slow it down a little bit
Then I started to think about
what kind of clothes
those vintage clothes
would look like
when I put them on
Then when I was thinking about it
I accidentally flipped the car
because I had to change the front and back
together, and the point was wrong
Then I thought, it's okay, I'll just fix it
Then I imagined
when I was searching online
for reference pictures
I found that many of them
have this kind of structure
The bottom is a triangle
and the sides are tighter
Sometimes I make some complex versions
but I don't make versions
I usually search online
I don't draw by myself
I search online
For example, if I want to make a coat
I search online for coat version
and then put the version
into MD
and then put it in the designer
After I have some changes
to the clothes
I will use 3D drawing tools
to draw some reference lines
on the clothes
Then I will turn
the reference line into the inner line
Then I can cut it
It seems that I didn't turn it
I just cut it
After cutting, there will be
such a opening
After I finished cutting
I started to imagine
what kind of dress
I want to make
I thought for a long time
and found that I haven't cut the back
Then I went back
to change my top
Actually, when I make
it's not very logical
I always look at the effect
and then change it
look at the effect
and change it
Then I think it's almost done
I may have to make
other modifications
For example, like sleeves
I see the reference
their sleeves are usually tight
Especially on the arm
So I will put
the point here
Adjust the position
Move them all up
So that the space
under the sleeves will be less
In fact, many times
Although it is used by
small friends in the fashion industry
But in fact, some knowledge
about fashion
There is still a certain understanding
If there is no
Maybe when it will be used
Sometimes it will be a little hard
So I saw a group of friends
Asked to use MD
Then I went to buy a dress
What kind of book
Then look there
I said wow this is too touching
Even when I was in college
I have read these books well
When I was learning at that time
I also read the book of the script
I just feel that
When I was in school
I haven't read the book of the script very seriously
As a result, when using the software
Instead of taking all those books
back
After that
Some modifications to the sleeves
Let me see
I still change here
It seems to change these lines in front
Make it look more round
Then sometimes
I will pull to the side
to see
I seem to feel here
Look at the side
It has some excess light
Then I was thinking
How to make it more flat
Then I found out at home
It's not flat anymore
Forget it, let's withdraw it
Yes
This is
Some people say that the most painful thing
After using MD is making panels
It's just like this
When modifying clothes
It will indeed take more time
But everyone can look forward to the future
version
Anyway, as far as I know
There will be a special one in the future
Very, very powerful
Just completely
You don't have a board
You can also change clothes quickly
A function
Everyone can look forward to
That new function
Although I don't know when it will be online
I am also old
I really want to give you
The function of gathering
But there is no way
Can't give you a few
Anyway, it's a quick change
No need to be like now
On the board
Fix it, fix it, fix it
Yes, do it again
Put the satellite
Yes, put the satellite
In fact, if you don't know how to make panels
In fact, you can go to that MD official
There are a lot of free
Free version can be downloaded
Then you can change it based on that
And when it comes to this
The one we bought
There will also be a big change
And then this big change
Because it can't be said
I'll just say it out loud
Is
Personal use
You can also upload clothes
Ha ha ha
Anyway, in the future
What will become more convenient
Including users
To do some
Is
Purchase of goods
And upload
It becomes the steam of the clothing industry
Oh yes
There will be one
Similar to the map workshop
It's open to everyone
It doesn't matter
Everyone will know sooner or later
Yes
When drawing lines
Press which line to switch
Just press the C key
Then
And then
The clothes we made in each live broadcast
Will be directly uploaded for free
That
It's a bit like the steam workshop
Then
These materials in each live broadcast
Will be directly
Put on the official website
So everyone
You can also directly
Download the project document
And this one
It should be very fast
Will be online as soon as possible
That's the live broadcast
These clothes
I will upload them all
So everyone
Just take a look
Just know how to use the function
Don't be too
Don't be too entangled with the board
And then
At this time
Which step is operated
Just add a layer of skirt to it
Then
Sometimes everyone is doing
Will find
If you look at the simulation
The bottom of the skirt may have some deformation
So you have to choose these lines
Set the elastic ratio to 100
It will no longer have deformation
Will be like before
Take it back
Then
I'm thinking
What is the skirt like
I actually read a lot of reference pictures
But I found
When I look at the reference pictures
The more
Because there are too many ideas
You are on a dress
When the real time is up
You will feel
I can't do this
I can't do that
What am I going to do
I don't know
Then I can only do the simplest things first
Then change the material
Then change the properties
Then change it while thinking
What am I going to do
Then here I changed the density
Because
When the density is relatively large
This skirt outside
Will be pressed to the skirt inside
If you put the density
It's the same as in the current world
If you change the density to 0
It doesn't matter
So it won't be pressed to the board
It's the same as in the current world
Then
When the original version has a certain bending rate, if you add it to the outside, there will be a breakage.
There will be a breakage beyond 100%.
So when I was using it, I completely forgot about it.
Then after I used it, I was cold-blooded.
I thought, wow, how did I record this too?
But it doesn't matter.
Every time I record these things by accident, I will give myself an explanation.
Just tell everyone, oh, don't follow this step.
In fact, it's because I accidentally forgot.
How to increase the wrinkle on the wrinkle line?
I don't understand.
Are you talking about the mark of the wrinkle?
Sometimes you can't increase it.
Sometimes you may find it.
I know there are some.
Anyway, it's on another computer.
Another computer below us.
But sometimes you can just use a sticker.
This kind of sticker is used to simulate this.
Is he talking about flexibility?
Is that what it means?
Flexibility.
Oh, I understand.
It's also possible.
You just choose a line.
Then add flexibility to the vertical editor.
Oh, this is when you use it.
You may find that you have a piece of fabric coming out.
Then you can use it.
Then you can use the selection grid tool.
Select this grid in the 2D window.
Then drag it in.
Separately put this whole grid in.
Or pull it out.
It can make the skirt stable.
Then I often do this kind of multi-layer clothing.
Hide the outer layer of the board.
Take a look at the shape inside.
Especially like this.
It's very complicated.
And there are a lot of panels.
You have to pay attention to whether the inner layer is unstable.
Because I also consider computer computing.
Like this kind of big panel.
If you want to simulate them together.
The computing speed of your computer must be very slow.
So I usually do a layer.
Will freeze a layer.
But because of the freezing.
It's a one-meter modification.
Other parts.
You have to be careful.
If it has something to do with it.
Sometimes the frozen panels.
It will cause some problems.
This is.
There is no way to avoid it.
Then.
So when you are freezing.
Be sure to remember.
Before you freeze a layer.
Be sure to simulate it with the inside first.
Simulation is stable.
Then you take a look at the inner layer.
Is there anything weird?
Then you freeze it again.
It can be solved with a layer.
But the layer is like this.
The layer itself is.
No problem.
But if you forget.
Application.
If you use layers.
Maybe your clothes.
There will be some sudden instability.
Anyway.
When doing multi-layer clothing.
If it's unstable.
You just put it on the layer.
A little higher.
Then if.
The layers are clearly high.
The layer is obviously very high, but it is still unstable, so you just set the layer to 0.
In the area of ​​the horizontal line, the degree to which the wrinkle is enhanced is obvious.
If you want to do this, I used to use a partial grid to divide it,
but with this one, the grid of that part will become more and more dense.
Then draw the inner line.
I draw the inner line here in order to add a circle to the edge in the middle.
In fact, it is also the same idea, that is, when making the edge of the circle,
as long as this plate is longer than the one you want to sew, there will be a wrinkle effect.
For example, the wrinkle of the sewing line of the CLO software,
the one you said is the Pockering function, right?
That function is not in MD, it is only in CLO.
Then this side is also, sometimes there is a grid like this,
you can use the selection of grid tools to pull it out separately.
It's good.
Yes, because it's accelerated,
so look,
it looks silky,
and if it's still unstable,
like me, I might use a layer,
and then pull it out,
pull it to a stable position.
In fact, when using MD,
sometimes my operation is very barbaric.
I don't like to use any selection network,
I usually just pull it with my hand,
choose a moving tool and just pull it,
and then I will reduce its particle strength,
so that its spine is smoother and more detailed.
In fact, this kind of thin, longer version,
in fact, it is OK to reduce the particle strength to 8 or 10.
See what's behind.
It's actually almost the same.
When dealing with this kind of border,
I might make a border in the 2D window,
and then adjust its position.
In short, in doing this kind of,
when doing this kind of multi-layered clothing,
you must remember to ensure that each layer is stable.
Only when each layer is stable,
you can record animation or change the posture afterwards,
it will be more stable.
Then it comes to the part of the sleeve.
On the sleeve side,
I choose to draw a round plate.
Its length is the same as the bottom of the sleeve.
Then I will expand the outline of the plate.
In fact, the total length of this outline of the plate
is the total length of the sleeve and the side of the sleeve.
Then sew it up.
But for this kind of round plate,
don't use the arrangement board.
Just use the arrangement board to move it.
Then here,
because I forgot to change its fabric,
so this fabric looks very, very hard.
Then I will change the fabric for it.
In MD,
if you want to do this kind of order of the sewing line,
first you can add some stickers to it.
If it is flat,
or in general,
it will be straight out.
Then you can take it out and put it in other 3D software.
Because the sewing wrinkle function,
it belongs to a,
it is,
anyway,
the sewing wrinkle in Clou,
it is just a hair line sticker.
Or it's just a higher sticker on top.
It's actually not a three-dimensional effect.
Because in Clou,
there are many people who use Clou,
clothes and clothes of clothing industry,
They are actually in an environment where they have just come into contact with 3D, so many of their friends don't use any other dyes or anything.
They may only have dyes in the front or side view.
Then, plus the internal dyes are dyes, so many friends in the clothing industry will choose to do dyes directly in the mold.
Then, they won't be involved in the three-dimensional or non-three-dimensional dyes.
Or whether it is a real grid, inward or outward.
So they just use a sticker to make an object.
So there is this function in CLO, which is the dyes function.
Of course, this function has a lot of friends who say that they hope that MB also has this function.
We also mentioned the development needs of that function.
But
There may not be a lot of people who mention this requirement.
The company just said that they don't want to develop it first.
When can the MD zipper be made into a physical model like a button?
Oh, I don't know.
I'll just ask.
There is no such plan, right?
No, it seems to have this plan.
It seems to be more difficult to make it.
Because of the zipper of the zipper.
When you want to use a different zipper, its grid is different.
The ruler may not be able to match it, right?
Yes, the ruler may not be able to match it.
So now it's all used to paste the picture first.
Yes, I see this question.
Then it's the effect of the front pull.
In fact, it's an original version.
Then put it out of the column.
Then lengthen the overall length of it.
Then there will be such a pull effect.
Because when the column is folded.
The lining line and the lining line.
Oh, it's not.
The lining line will automatically form between the inner line or the outer line of the board.
In this way, you can reduce its strength.
Then simulate a layer separately.
Oh, like me.
He fought because I forgot that I had set the level.
And I don't believe it.
I don't think it's a problem.
I'll pull it back and simulate it again.
And then I found it wrong at the end.
It turned out to be my problem.
Can the ending increase the fold step by step?
Yes, you can.
You have to select the grid tool.
Select a area.
Then select the right button.
There is a grid detail.
In the detail part.
If you have that.
If you have a grid.
If you have fold.
If it has a fold itself.
The fold will be more obvious.
Or sometimes I recommend you to just use that.
This tool.
this this
Oh wrong wrong.
Not the one just now.
This is like a movement.
It is ourijo function.
When using the jaggy function.
Then you go along the sewing line.
Or that line that produces a fold.
If you use the correct number to smear one side, it will add wrinkles.
Because it is actually equivalent to increasing that piece of board.
It's getting wider and bigger.
I usually recommend that you use it directly.
We call this a tortoise, a tortoise tool.
Then go to the operation, there will be wrinkles.
This is me changing the model's posture.
Then when the whole set of clothes is done,
If you change the posture, the effect of the clothes will also change.
Then here I want to add a hat to it.
So I changed the round board first.
Then sew it to the head with a small sewing needle.
Then the hat board will stick to the model's head.
It won't fall down.
Then because the computer runs too slow, I can't stand it.
I reactivated the other parts of the board.
After I reactivated it, I started to adjust the hat.
First of all, I was thinking about the shape of the hat.
I will drag it to see the overall shape.
Then I stopped here for a while.
I went to see the reference picture.
After looking at the reference picture, I chose to sew two points with a sewing needle.
After sewing two points,
The middle part is gone.
Anyway, the middle part is that you can set the length of the sewing line with a sewing needle.
After setting the length, this area will not change.
The distance between these two points will be fixed.
After fixing the distance, your overall shape will not change.
After that, I will add a circle to the side of the hat.
In fact, it is the effect of making hats.
Then I found that after sewing, I found that the sewing line is in front.
I will adjust the sewing line along the edge of this circle of the sewing box.
Then the sewing line is hidden behind.
The opening is hidden behind.
Then sew the top plate on it.
It is a hat top on the hat.
After sewing, I found that I forgot that there is a hole in the middle of the hat.
I have been using a 10-star hat plate.
When I changed to the back of the model, I found that I made it into a 10-star hat.
Then I modified it.
Adjust its position.
Because there are more sewing needles used before.
There is also a type of sewing line here.
I set a folding angle.
Otherwise, because the plate is default, it is connected smoothly.
If you do not set a folding angle, it will not fold like the hat in real life.
I will make it like this.
I think I will speak a little faster when I get to MD.
I don't think you will be tired.
But it doesn't matter.
You can watch the video of the back version.
I will talk about it in more detail in that video.
Then I look again.
What should this hat be worn?
What position should I wear this hat?
Then I found that in the process of adjusting my hat in various ways
The shape of this hat has changed
I thought it was better to delete all these fake red needles
Just freeze the middle one
Then simulate the side
Let this board pass by itself
After passing by, adjust it manually
Anyway, I'm doing this kind of static
When I don't use these models for recording animation
I will be confused
What angle should I choose to make the final simulation
So I will just do it wherever I can't see
So what I'm most afraid of is to hear
For example, I said to my colleagues
Can you help me make that poster?
Then the lady who made the poster told me
Can you change the angle
Then I heard this
When I hear this, I will think
Well, okay
Oh, it's like a belly
So many wrinkles
It's just a colon
Then stretch it a little longer
80% don't understand
Really
I think we may be more nervous today
It's faster
It's okay
You can watch the video later
Sorry, I'm too much
No, it's okay
Everyone actually
I also listen to it very carefully
I also
If it wasn't for him
If you say it's been a long time
I didn't even realize
Some of the past
Then I want to do it here
Because I feel like they are
It seems to have this kind of interface
It's a corner that will lift the skirt
Then here I will add a corner
Put it around the model's wrist
I just want to do one of those
Well, it's like this
The lady is asking someone else
The action
Then I took this skirt
The posture of the hand is also adjusted in advance
Then use a sewing needle
Add two sewing needles
Sew it to the model's hand
This will have a kind of
Take up the feeling of the dress
Happy time
Happy time is always short
Yeah
It feels like it's gone in a blink of an eye
Then slightly modify it
The position of the sewing needle
Then take a look
How to put this skirt on the wrist
More natural
Then I pull it far
Look closer
I think it's almost OK
When I
I might freeze it
Then do the back
What am I doing here
I seem to be here
See if there is a strange bug
Is there
See if this dress
Is there anything wrong with it
I will save it if there is nothing
Because I
I'm afraid of sudden crashes
And other problems
After that, make a necklace
Like a necklace
I was in the group before
I have shared with you
A pearl necklace made of thread
This is a ball from the outside
Then as a necklace
Then put it on the board
It will directly connect to a string of necklaces
Then let's lower the
The back of the board is solid
Let it stick around the model
Stick around
After sticking around
In fact, it's almost
Like this
I think it has some cracks
Then I want to say
Change its size
Then after changing
I found that the cracks are bigger
I just
All right
I'll go back and adjust it
Some other numbers
You will see some cracks here
In fact, this crack
Like a celebrity
Sometimes there are some
Problems with deformation
Basically because of the board itself
It has some deformation problems
So you have to reduce the strength of the board
This way, it will be attached to the top thread
Will
It's not that much of a deformation
Then I'm looking for
Why is there a little deformation?
Because the strength is actually reduced
Later, I replaced it
Rearrange the grid
Make its grid arrangement more neat
Then simulate again
When I simulate
The thread will disappear
At this time
I found it normal after simulation
Because when I rearrange the grid
Is the grid arrangement more neat?
Then I will put the current
This action is saved
Save as a posture
Then I can do some things later
Yes
In Maya
In Maya Max
This kind of configuration
It will be more convenient
Then because
I don't know how to use
So basically what I can do in MD
Do it in MD
Then here is almost the whole process
In fact, it is also relatively fast
Then this is the last project file
Can you see this project file?
In the middle, in fact, it is
I added some materials to it
Like this kind of pattern
And the pattern on the sleeve side
Then there is also the above insert
It's almost here
Do you have any questions about MD?
Any question is fine
Hello hello
Do you have any friends?
Ada, when you usually use MD
Is there any problem?
It seems that there is no problem
Really?
Just the GPU
If it can be calculated better
It's perfect
Basically there is no problem
One of the plans is to optimize the GPU simulation
There is also a function similar to Cremash
Ah, if I can have it, I'll save it
Yes, because this can save most of the transfer
What kind of problem
Yes yes yes
But this is still in development
Including its own thickness
If it can automatically remesh
Then turn on a thickness
Then it's done directly
Wow, that's really great
Yes, this is in one of our main projects
Top
There is no such function in the top function
Similar to the relaxation cloth line
What kind of function is the relaxation cloth line?
Similar to what
Similar to the smooth brush
Let's say that
There is a point in an area
Automatically
Smooth
Ah, I actually
Generally if I want to do this
I might go to
The sculpt mode
Is the sculpt mode of MD
Oh, use the sculpt mode to release
Then use the smooth brush to brush
But the smooth brush will
Change the shape
Yes, the shape
But I usually do it like this
Because I actually rarely involve
Uh, I'm going to
To adjust these grid
Because when it comes to the top
To loosen the grid
This is a very important function
Because there is no such function now
So now if
I used to try to use MD
To do the top
I will need to do one
A model with a very small number of faces
Um
Then after every point is done well
Then add a line to the top
Then get a more dense model
Because I can't
Loosen it again
Um
That's just
I can only use this way of thinking
If there is a tool to loosen
It will be better
Oh, I understand
I can mention this
Functional development needs
I think this should be
A function that can be added earlier
Good good good
Yes
I listen to it
I think it sounds like
It feels reasonable
Then it shouldn't be very difficult
It shouldn't be very difficult
Anyway, we often
Just this kind of feature request
Provide
Provide the programmer effect
And then the pressure is transferred to them
Is it directly
It can be submitted to the development department in South Korea, right?
Yes
What we said
Go back to the topic
Generally, it is directly submitted to the development department
Then they will
According to
Usually
Uh, more comments are mentioned
Or they have their own plans
For example, this itself is in their planning blueprint
This can be updated as soon as possible
Hey, in fact, if there is
That kind of development roadmap of MD
It would be better to see it publicly
Because there are actually a lot of other software
There will be similar
For example, at the beginning of this year
It will announce one of their
This year's roadmap
Then that
Everyone knows
Do you know what he is updating this year?
There will be one
There is a
There is a such expectation
In fact, if MD can also have this
Oh, we don't seem to have this
I don't know why we don't have this
Maybe because we are really developing
This is the development of each year
Uh, there are a lot of content to be developed
Then
Uh, I'm not sure what it is
It must be developed
There is no
Not in the expectation
Many times
I'm afraid of jumping
So generally we don't say it in advance
Then it's when this feature is really released
We will say
Oh, we have to be more cautious
I dare not say
If you mention this feature this year
And then say it was not developed
It's too embarrassing
Yeah
And because of us
In fact, we set it up first
That one
Uh, it's almost
The time to announce the next version
Then before this deadline
Yeah
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
Everyone is trying to develop the function
It's just
Didn't you say that the deadline is the first productivity
The closer you get to the deadline
We will
Uh, anyway, it's speed
fast
OK
Actually, the most exciting thing is the Gpu
If this piece can be changed
It's really perfect
In fact, this is right
Then
I think it's because of the GPU simulation.
Because we started with the CPU simulation,
whether it's GPU or CPU,
the CPU has a high capacity.
Yes, because if the capacity is particularly high,
if MD starts the decoding mode,
if you rotate the view,
it is actually in a state of pause.
After you loosen it, it will continue to decode.
If you have a lot of computing pressure,
and then you forget to rotate the view,
and then it turns on and off,
then it's over.
Yes, so these are all the plans we are currently optimizing,
especially the GPU.
But the difficulty of optimizing is quite high,
so we have been thinking about it.
Yes, there is also the name of the material.
Oh.
The name of the fabric.
I know.
People often want Chinese and Chinese characters.
Yes, because in fact,
after all, people who use this software
are not from the clothing industry.
We don't know anything about this thing,
and then it's all in English.
It's just very confusing.
I can only understand cotton,
and then I can understand muslin,
and then I don't know what silk is.
I can understand trim,
I can understand wool,
and then the ones in the back,
the long ones,
I don't know what they are at all.
Yes, we had a friend before
who shared the Chinese name,
but it seems to be because our software itself
is developed in Korea,
and then if the Chinese characters are in the installation package,
there will be some bugs.
Or it's not in the library right now,
in the library function,
it doesn't have a fabric library.
Can that icon be made into Chinese?
I'll take a look at the icon.
Oh, my icon.
You mean the name?
Yes, that's it.
Oh, his name is the same as what we said before.
Doesn't he have a preview icon?
This little icon,
because it's not a picture,
this is not a picture,
this is automatically generated.
This is automatically generated?
Yes.
This is because it's automatically generated,
plus his name is actually following that,
he's actually the same thing as this side,
and these here,
they're just in the same folder.
And then it's because of this name,
if it's because we put it in the installation package itself,
it's actually a reverse icon,
and then you put them together,
and then like this,
if it's in Chinese,
it will cause some problems in the installation process.
Oh, I thought that the icon was the icon file,
and then it can be modified through that icon,
the image can be modified,
and then it turns out that it's automatically generated.
Yes, so we can only let everyone know about this Chinese question in the later stage,
you're just,
just put that,
where's the meaning of this icon?
The meaning of this icon is actually to let you,
to let you preview the file,
what it looks like when you put it on,
but it doesn't actually change the shape,
you have to put the mouse on it to have a preview.
Yes, it's just a color.
Haha.
Extra Chinese bag,
we can,
I can talk to them about it,
but in fact,
the extra Chinese things are all thrown into the group.
I didn't just tell everyone that we now have a Chinese bag,
everyone is going to get it in the group.
This kind of,
I can write a post or something,
an announcement,
click on these things in the Chinese bag.
I saw that there is a Fabric CN and EN Excel table in the group.
Oh, the Excel table is organized by us,
that is,
if you click on it,
you can see that there are some extra yellow,
that is,
the list of extra yellow,
extra orange,
is for everyone to remember that these are the most common ones.
If you don't know how to use others,
you can use these alone.
Then it has a list that says what kind of fabric is used on what kind of clothes.
Yes, yes, yes,
this is very good,
the point of use is very good,
because in fact,
some of you,
even if you write it in Chinese,
you don't know what it is,
for example,
Paris,
and Hada,
and vinegar,
vinegar,
and cloth,
I don't know what it is,
yes,
so we just wrote a table like this,
and it's organized,
if you don't know what fabric to use,
then you just look at it,
just use it.
It's good,
yes,
this is good,
put it in the group,
and then,
I,
oh,
But in fact, if we don't say that there are some very clear words that we usually use MD ourselves, I usually make them by hand.
I didn't expect that I was the kind of person who used default fabric and then made it by hand.
Wow, that's amazing.
This is what it might be like if you use it for a long time.
But I think this is indeed a piece of painting that is indeed a relatively important piece.
Maybe I'll talk to them about these questions in the future.
In fact, there are some Chinese words in physical attributes that are actually quite hard to understand.
For example, it says,
What's the difference between these two?
The strength of the tail gauze is actually the stretchiness of the tail gauze.
This fabric is easier to stretch.
For example, this fabric is harder to stretch.
This is the strength of the tail gauze.
It's the stretchiness of the tail gauze.
And then the one at the back is a bend.
It's similar to the strength of the bend deformation.
But it has a bend strength.
But it also has a special bend.
That is, the strength of the tail gauze.
There is a bend strength of the tail gauze below.
And a deformation rate.
This is the strength of the tail gauze.
Right.
The deformation rate of the tail gauze and the deformation strength of the tail gauze.
Then I was confused.
Oh, the tail gauze is actually the fabric.
It's in the shape of a gold tail.
After choosing this tool, it's in the shape of a gold tail.
This arrow, its direction, the direction parallel to the arrow is the gold gauze.
And then the 90 degree is the tail gauze.
There are some clothes.
For example, when we normally wear clothes,
It's usually less elastic in the vertical direction.
Because the length of a whole piece of clothing is basically fixed.
But it's very similar.
Because people have fat and then they have different parts.
The distribution of the flesh is different.
So the tail is very similar.
Its stretchability is generally better.
Then consider the factors in real life.
So the physical properties are divided into gold tail gauze.
That is, horizontal and vertical.
I can understand the gold tail gauze.
It's just that its strength and bending strength and deformation strength.
It's specific.
For example, the first strength above it should be called stretching strength, right?
It's actually stretching strength.
The second bending strength.
I can understand bending strength.
Then bending strength, gold gauze, tail gauze.
There's another one down there.
That's the overall bending strength.
Oh, that's the oblique line.
The bending strength of the oblique line.
Then what does its deformation rate mean?
The deformation rate is whether an object is able to deform easily.
But isn't stretching and bending also part of its deformation?
Yes, so let me tell you.
Actually, after I explained it, you will find that its translation is very difficult.
This deformation rate refers to an object.
Whether it is able to deform due to external stretching.
If this value is very high, it is very easy to deform due to external stretching.
But the bending strength above it is not due to external strength.
Or is it due to its own weight?
Yes, it is due to its own weight.
Whether it is able to bend or not.
But the deformation rate is actually the most obvious part of this oblique line.
Because when it comes to the oblique line, it doesn't form a force.
Then it turns into a force.
And then it turns into this clothes.
Now it becomes a physics class.
And then when this value is relatively high, it is very easy to deform due to external strength.
These wrinkles in the oblique line will disappear.
But other parts, for example, it may only disappear in the oblique line.
The wrinkles in other parts are still there.
So the deformation rate is actually the most obvious.
The most obvious part is where the oblique line is.
If the deformation rate is...
Including some oblique lines that are elastic.
Including some oblique lines that have angles.
It will be more pronounced in terms of the deformation rate.
Yes, these wrinkles in the oblique line.
If you want these wrinkles to be obvious, you have to adjust the deformation rate to zero.
Because it is not easy to deform.
It is not easy to stretch.
So it will become zero.
If you want it to become powerful, you have to adjust it to zero.
Yes.
And then if you want all the wrinkles here to disappear, you have to adjust it all to 100.
Because it is easy to deform.
It is easy to deform due to external stretching.
So it's hard to understand, right?
It's just a very difficult one.
What should it be called?
For example, anti-deformation rate.
Oh, but how do you say it?
Deformation rate.
Oh, that's right.
Yes.
Anti-external force.
This feeling.
Yes.
So we've been thinking about this translation.
Should it be.
That is to say, in MD.
These are some of the things that make it easier to understand.
Is it possible, for example, to put the mouse on top of it?
After jumping out of a small GIF animation.
Oh, that's a good idea.
Because in fact.
In that.
I used a 3D printing software before.
And then it has such a property of the external mirror and the internal mirror.
And on top of a resistance property.
It's a very, very hard to understand thing.
And then later in the latest version.
He just put the mouse on it.
There will be an animation.
And then everyone understands.
Oh, I understand.
I think this should be pretty good.
There's a preview animation when the mouse is on top of it, right?
This is also possible.
Yes, yes.
The technology.
Sorry.
Featured.
Power development needs.
And then he blacked you out.
They won't black me out.
Because we're all on a mission board.
Added up.
Pretty good.
Oh, the kind of thing like a trailer.
Yes, he can't black me out.
We'll add a lot of things on top of it.
And then.
And I usually let Jimmy add it.
Like, like Zbrush.
He's like this.
Zbrush.
If you put the mouse on it, there will be a short view.
And then.
But this plan seems to be cut off, I think it should be OK to add these built-ins, it should be OK, I'm not sure either, because to be honest, in the next version of MD, because our interface has all changed, this interface is the last old version of MD interface, in the time of Marvelous Designers, until 10.5, the next version of MD, all the interfaces will change.
Oh, that's not it, we have to re-select it again.
Oh, it won't be re-selected, the core function is still the same, it's just that the UI has changed, which is very different from the current UI.
Because now it feels like the UI has no place to put buttons, the buttons are already layered, and we still don't have enough space.
Yes, by then, these windows, like the object window, the editor will become available, it can be switched, and then add the perspective.
Before, there were always friends who said they wanted to see two things.
For example, the front view and the side view, they want to see them at the same time.
Oh, the module window, right?
Yes, I know.
After that, the UI will become like that.
But I feel that this built-in should still be able to do it.
I accidentally became a leak again.
I seem to have a lot of new features.
It's okay.
In fact, your hair department is also very close.
The software company.
Oh, it's like this.
Chinese translation is also translated by me.
Yes, all the translations in the software are also translated by me.
Then, because when we are translating, the translation is not very abstract.
You can clearly know where this word appears.
Because it's in the program.
I know it gives you a text, and then you flip it over to the text.
This is a table, and then you don't even know where this is.
Yes, you don't even know where it is.
You can only guess where this word is based on its premise.
Because I have also done software translation.
I also know that you often don't know where this thing appears when you flip it over.
Yes, and then sometimes when you flip it over, you may have to say to your colleagues,
I'm sorry, where is this word?
Then he will tell you, I don't know where this word is either.
Yes, when he was developing software, he was actually using all the words in this table in a table.
So he didn't just say one function and one name.
He doesn't necessarily have this word.
He must be in this position.
He may have used this word in several places.
I know this.
It's really not easy to translate.
But I feel like I need to record this tonight.
Maybe next week.
I'll think about it when I go back next week.
Next time in our software,
Should these translations be replaced with a better understanding of the vocabulary?
But if it changes like this,
Because our handbook has a lot of names that are in line with this.
It means I have to put all the...
Because I flipped the handbook, too.
I gave you a hole.
It's okay.
It doesn't matter.
And then I have to change this translation at the same time.
Actually, it's not bad.
It's really not much.
Maybe it's because our team hasn't expanded yet.
So there are a lot of things to do.
It's a bit more complicated.
But it's okay. I quite like to do translation.
I think that's all the questions I wanted to ask.
I don't think there are any other questions.
Let's check the chats.
Do you have any questions?
Do you have any other questions?
You are also welcome to ask questions in the group chat.
There is also a group chat in A.
You can ask questions in A.
What is your group name?
I forgot again.
The official group name of Marvelous Designer is
1081139721.
You are all welcome to join the official group of Marvelous Designer.
The group leader is the one we are live streaming right now.
This is Xue Li.
Xue Li.
Actually, it's your group name in A.
So I wrote our group name on B.
The group name is 535463343.
535463343.
You are all welcome to join the discussion.
If you have any special questions,
you can also chat with me.
I can also answer your questions.
Wow, your voice is very good.
It's like a radio.
Really?
Thank you.
Your moon, my star.
It's very standard.
It has the potential to be broadcasted.
Very good.
Okay, I understand.
Maybe one day,
you will debut as a dubbing artist.
Yes, you can make a live 2D image.
Then you can hang it on the next live streaming.
I'll teach you how to use OBS.
Then you can hang a small live 2D on it.
Then you can debut.
Actually, I thought about it before.
Should I do it?
But I can only think about it in my mind.
Because there are so many other things.
I originally wanted to say,
I feel that the official of Marvelous Design,
first of all, the image of Hannah,
can also be made into a live 2D with her as the blueprint.
Then we can also put it underneath when we are live streaming.
It's cute.
But just think about it.
I recently appeared in OBS,
a live 2D production.
This is a whole process of teaching how to solve the live broadcast.
As long as you have an example,
you can follow the teaching.
You can do it until you can live stream at the end.
Okay.
I'll watch it now.
I'll watch it right after I'm done.
Because in addition to doing Marvelous Design,
it's our official live streaming.
I also have another live streaming.
My own live streaming.
I'm doing a game live streaming.
So there is a debut, right?
Just debuted.
Yes.
I'm surprised.
I'm surprised to debut.
Is it like this?
From now on, I'll be Snowflake-official.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
You have to add official.
It's more professional.
Yes.
Actually, speaking of this,
I used to be in our company.
This is the name of Bilibili.
The name of this account.
Many of my friends asked,
ah, why is this official still scolding people?
Say our official account number.
I know everyone is kidding.
But it's because Marvelous Design is too long.
If it's called Marvelous Designer Official,
Bilibili says your name is too long.
Change the name.
If it's called Marvelous Designer Official,
then Bilibili will still say your name is too long.
Can you change your name?
Then finally we try it.
Only MD official.
The length is just right.
If it's called Marvelous Designer,
it won't work.
it will be too long.
Oh, that's too bad.
There's nothing we can do.
Yes, so many of my friends
searched us on Bilibili at the beginning.
But they couldn't find us.
They couldn't find our official account number.
Because...
It must be very strange for a lot of people
to enter the live broadcast room.
Why is the screen not moving?
Two people are chatting.
Oh, is that so?
Then I'll move it again.
I'll move it while talking.
Because the screen is stopped.
Oh, MD official.
But if it's MD official,
I don't think everyone can understand what it is.
I just said MD's official name is very strange.
It feels like I'm listening to a radio station.
It's really big.
It's a potato.
Dodozi is also an old audience of our live broadcast.
It's also a friend who often appears in the group.
Don't the old audience have a sword?
Oh, let me see.
Is there a captain?
There is no captain.
No one.
No one has a sword.
It's very simple.
Yes, today's live broadcast is almost over.
Everyone has nothing.
Oh, I want to ask how to move the sticker up and down.
The sticker uses this tool.
This adjustment sticker tool.
Or the editing texture tool next to it.
Sometimes if you are the texture of the bottom, you can use it.
And then if you are an extra sticker.
Graphics, you can use the editor.
I'm just spinning.
You just click and drag.
It's flat.
I'm looking for a piece.
Is there anything else?
Now you can directly read the Substance sticker.
This is really good.
Yes, you can read the Substance directly.
And then some of the settings in it can also be opened here.
Yes, that's the Substance Designer.
The properties that are exposed in the designer can be adjusted directly in MD.
Yes.
But because there is no home back sticker in MD.
So those related to home back can't be adjusted.
Related to home back.
For example, based on AO production.
Or the kind that is based on coverage production.
There's no way.
Yes.
When does MD add a home back?
We only have...
Just add a home back to the top.
The home back that we have in our software is only the home back of the home UV picture.
Other than that, we don't have any.
And then you just flip all the home back software.
And then you just make a human shape of the lower model.
And then you put it in.
And then MD makes clothes directly.
And then make the top.
And then the home back.
And then SP makes the stickers.
Yes.
SP doesn't need to make stickers.
If there is a home back.
Put the material made by SD directly into MD.
And then it can be directly based on the home back stickers.
To expose the properties to be adjusted.
And then you can just show the picture.
MD adds another rendering function.
We...
We started from the beginning.
Is just doing fabric calculation.
Why now?
Add so many functions in MD.
Now there is not that.
MD has a high quality display.
High quality display function.
That's great.
Just press it.
And then you can have that.
This is a good display effect.
This is really good.
This effect.
It also brings the effect of AO.
And there is one.
It feels a bit like that.
Similar to the effect of using DX11 or 12.
It's a high quality display.
This is pretty good.
This.
It's a pity that it can't be adjusted.
Marker.
Now there is actually a marker.
But the tool of marking.
Well.
Everyone knows.
That's good.
Because I know that everyone.
I'm used to using other software to mark.
Markers in Marvellous Designer can only be used as initials.
Or some.
I was not kidding before.
I said I would use ZB.
ZB as a board.
ZB's Spotlight as a board.
And then put it in ZB to calculate.
After the calculation, put it in MD to mark.
I thought this idea was pretty good.
It is.
Back to a MD Marker tutorial.
I think it will be used to half.
Because now MD can be divided into software.
And then.
Cooperate with software.
And then use MD's Marker function.
It should be quite useful.
But.
But I have a question.
After the carving, you will solve the problem.
Yes.
Maybe it's good for those who want to keep some parts of the body.
Oh, this one.
Oh, no.
The overall atmosphere is very good.
Especially the waist of the pleated skirt.
It's just perfect.
I think Ada just gave some comfort after she accidentally put on some clothes.
If you can make it harder,
for example, you can carve some very small details on some clothes.
For example, the skirt or the edge of the seam line.
Then I can use the carving tool to carve some small details.
I tried it like this before.
I said I don't carve the overall shape.
Can it be calculated?
I'll carve some of the effects that I just mentioned in the Closed 3D.
For example, I use a carving brush to carve it out.
I use a straight brush.
Then I carve it out.
But once it's done, it's gone.
So if there is a partial hardening, it's very good.
Yes, and this calculation will be a little less than the partial freezing.
Because now some of you may have used partial freezing.
Partial freezing is also similar to maintaining the shape of an area in this way.
But if it's partial freezing, it will have a very high computer calculation.
So although we now have a partial freezing.
Actually, it's the same as the seam line.
After choosing a piece of seam line web, it's partial freezing.
But the computer's printing speed will be very, very, very slow.
Because actually, the carving function is particularly practical.
I don't know if I can talk about it.
I have a friend who does the flat-line project.
Then the flat-line project, the flat-line 2 project.
Then the requirement in it is to completely do the original painting.
What kind of painting do you need to do in MD?
There is such a requirement.
And then if you use the carving function, you can quickly get it to that size.
Because some of the steps of the painter, if you use the W key to drag, it's actually hard to drag it out as you want.
But you can quickly achieve that size with the carving tool.
Oh, yes.
There is also a function in MD10 now.
I don't know if you have used it.
It's actually a little similar to this.
It's in the carving mode.
You can drag it out with your hand.
But you don't have to do the simulation.
You can do the dynamic work directly in the carving mode.
Oh, it's similar to Blender and Zbrush's new dynamic brush.
Yes.
For example, if you go to drag it out.
Then there is no way to live after ZB solves it.
Hahaha.
You can drag it out like this.
And then you can do it here.
Just like dragging.
Sometimes there are some places where the details are focused.
Maybe you want it to be a little bit more like this.
Turn it a little bit.
Oh, yes.
This one is fine.
Take a look.
Ah, carve it out.
No.
Carving.
I'm not good at carving.
I don't show how to carve.
The dynamic ZB brush is quite useful.
Because it has those identification layers.
You can take two layers together.
This is also shown in the video that introduces the new feature.
You can go and have a look.
Yes.
There's also a group of people saying that Marvelous Diana's official website is on the mainland.
Oh, yes.
Yes.
Our official website server is on Amazon.
And then he has a plan to sign the Chinese official website into the domestic platform.
But this is still in the plan.
I don't know if it's going to be on.
Yes.
So now it's on the Internet.
Sometimes it's going to be slower.
Sometimes it's fast.
Sometimes it's slow.
But in general, it's all.
It's good to be able to jump from Ali Yun or Tencent Yun.
It will be faster.
Yes.
This is what we planned.
I feel like time has passed so long today.
It's been a very long time.
It's already 10 o'clock.
Yes.
I didn't expect it to be so long today.
It's all my fault.
I'm sorry.
I stopped at 10 o'clock.
It's too much.
No, it's not.
I said 40 minutes.
I said 20 minutes.
No.
I don't think it's been long.
I just sighed.
It's a happy time.
I think the weather is always so fast.
OK.
I don't think you have any questions.
If you don't have any questions,
We can go to the end of the audition today.
Is there any other questions?
No problems.
No problem.
A is more busy.
Because A really seems to be very serious about this.
I'm really tired for this live broadcast, I prepared so much content and it's very interesting to talk about it, I'm also very happy to hear it.
Thank you, thank you, it's not hard, it's not hard, this is what it should be, it should be.
Ada is very interesting to talk about these lessons, but also very detailed, I also watched Ada's video from 0 to ZB, I also learned it secretly, with Ada.
I also hope everyone can support Ada.
Ada is really a very, very, very, very, very, very professional,
and a very, very patient teacher.
Everyone, please support MD's official social media accounts.
Please click and follow, if you have some free time, you can also click on the arrow.
Oh, the commercial support.
And also MD's official group, the atmosphere of this group is really good,
everyone is talking about that, I see that they talk a lot,
they are all talking about that.
They talk about software, some operating techniques, and so on.
They don't talk much.
Basically, they are all photographing, and then they send in some things related to MD.
You are like my three-dimensional study group, most people are talking about it.
They usually talk about something like hardware, and then some comics, animation, and so on.
Anyway, they don't talk about three dimensions when they talk about anything.
Yes, the atmosphere of the MD group is very good.
I feel that the group is also very good.
The MD group, I always thought that the MD group was very professional,
and then when I saw that kind of very, very professional group,
I would wonder if there would be a lot of pressure to join.
I feel that everyone around me is a big boss, so...
No, everyone in this group is idle, everyone is idle,
and then only I will occasionally look at the group, and then I will send an expression of talking about CG,
and then everyone will be silent, and then we will continue to talk for a while.
I understand, I understand.
This is the water group.
Tomorrow I will be the dragon king of the MD group and the A group.
The dragon king of both groups is me.
Okay, if you have any MD usage problems, you can also add this group,
the official group of Marvelous Design.
In the lower left corner, there is a group called 1081139721,
and then there is a password in the lower left corner of this video.
Okay.
Then after you add it in, if you usually have MD problems,
you can ask in this group, and then someone will answer you.
And then if there are any three-dimensional production problems,
you can also talk to me alone,
and there are a lot of dragons in this group, and you can also add my group.
Just add the MD group first.
And then if there are any MD problems,
in fact, in general, I see that Jimmy is answering in the group, right?
In fact, I also have to answer.
But now in order to let Jimmy write more content,
there are some questions that will let him come back.
If you have very difficult questions, you can ask me.
There are no other difficult questions.
You can send it directly to the group.
Or we also welcome everyone to chat with us in private or in the group.
It's okay.
The atmosphere of the whole group is still okay.
Okay.
MD is really a very good software.
I suggest everyone to try it.
It's really a good software.
It really changed the industry.
When we were in the game and film industry,
we did it manually.
It was really done manually.
About ten years ago,
we used the Maya carding tool to card each cloth little by little.
Later, after we had ZBrush,
we might have carved it accordingly.
Not only ten years ago,
but more than ten years ago,
we were all carded.
Later, after we had ZBrush,
we started to carve the wrinkles manually.
At that time, we had to learn a lot of the structure of the cloth.
Then a few years ago,
after MD appeared,
everyone just let it go.
These things don't need to be learned anymore.
It's automatically solved.
It's really very good.
It changed the software of the entire industry.
Including now,
big film and television companies are using it.
For example,
companies such as Industrial Lighting and Vita are all using it.
All the big film and television companies are using it.
Game companies are also using it.
For example,
we are using this software in the entire game industry.
It's really a very good software.
If you are interested,
you can try it.
You will know that
this software is super stupid.
It's not that complicated.
I'll lie to you first,
right?
I understand.
From now on,
I will record this sentence,
and I will start to memorize it now.
Then,
I will hear it every time.
I said,
I will memorize this sentence of A.D.A.
Then,
this A.D.A.
will come out.
Then,
this A.D.A.
will come out.
Then,
this A.D.A.
will come out.
Then,
this A.D.A.
will come out.
Then,
this A.D.A.
will come out.
Then,
this A.D.A.
will come out.
Then,
this A.D.A.
will come out.
Then,
this A.D.A.
will come out.
Then,
this A.D.A.
will come out.
This is what they are using.
Well,
I've learned it.
A.D.A.
is more famous than Xelian.
That's why they introduced that.
Yes.
Well,
welcome everyone.
actually,
you may hear me to be young.
Actually,
If a software is able to have this level of friendliness in an industry,
this software is generally not difficult to use.
For example, Substance Painter, which also appeared at the same time as AMD a few years ago,
is not very complicated.
It is also very simple.
It almost covers the friendliness of the entire sticker part at once.
So is AMD.
If it is difficult to use, it will not be used by many people.
For example, software like Mari is very difficult to use.
Although it works well, only people in the film industry can use it.
But software like SP is used by everyone.
AMD is also very easy to use.
It's easy to get started.
That's why so many people are willing to use it.
In addition, its features are very powerful.
So it has such a high friendliness rate all at once.
So don't be afraid of this kind of software.
It's hard to use a very famous software.
In fact, it's not difficult to use.
It's much simpler than software like Maya MX.
Its learning curve is actually very smooth.
It's just that the difficult part is not the software part,
but the part where the real clothing is cold.
It's more difficult.
It's just that the part where the real clothing is cold.
If you think Marvelous Designer is not so easy to use,
please watch Ada's tutorials.
You can buy it on the BulkCG.
Or you can check out Ada's tutorials.
Ada's tutorials are not just Marvelous Designer.
There are also other 3D software,
including Maya and Bulk.
And then...
You can check it out on BulkCG.
I have...
How many pages do I have?
I have 7 pages.
1 2 3.
I have over 60 tutorials.
And half of them are free to watch.
You can watch them at will.
There are various kinds of software.
Yes, I think watching Ada's videos is...
It's just like watching the fried video of Wang Gang.
When you watch other people's videos,
it's probably to learn how to cook fried dishes.
When you watch Ada's videos,
If you watch Ada's videos, you will learn how to open a restaurant.
From the beginning to the end, whether it is the most basic content or some very in-depth and difficult to understand content,
Ada can explain in great detail and then try to use some simplified methods to complete such operations.
I think these are very, very, very, very, very rare.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
And thank you very much, Ada, for being our guest today.
No, no, no, I'm very honored.
I'm very honored to be invited by MD China to do a live broadcast at Bilibili.
Thank you very, very much for giving me this opportunity.
Thank you, everyone.
Thank you so much for coming to watch this live broadcast.
Yes.
Thank you, everyone, for your support all the time.
We will try our best to give you, especially friends in China, some benefits and so on.
We also hope that you can participate more often.
We actually have a lot of ideas and opportunities to let everyone use MAMAS.
Including some competitions, some of these headlines.
Yes.
These are all opportunities to win or be selected.
Some MAMAS, to give some MAMAS to our users.
We also hope that everyone can pay more attention to our usual movements.
Everyone, pay attention.
Thank you.
We usually draw prizes.
Be sure to pay attention.
Watch every live broadcast.
Yes, yes, yes.
Thank you, everyone, for coming to watch our live broadcast tonight.
And thank you, A-da.
Again, thank you, A-da, for being willing to participate in our live broadcast.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
You brought us so much popularity.
Many, many of our friends came from A-da.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
It's getting late today.
It's time to say goodbye to everyone.
See you tomorrow.
Happy times are so short.
Right?
Happy times.
It's hard to forget the good times.
Well, that's it for today.